巨人
补充翻译 校对: 寻找自己的猫
There he is. There's the stallion. That's War Winds.
就是那匹马 它是匹种马 名叫"战风"
Beautiful.
真漂亮
That's my daughter riding him. Leslie.
骑着它的是 我女儿莱斯莉
Leslie's my daughter. She's riding him.
骑着那匹马的 是我女儿莱斯莉
Doctor, that sure is a beautiful animal.
医生 这匹马真是漂亮极了
Yes. Well, we'll get to the horses first thing in the morning.
明天早上我们再去看马
Right now you're coming up to the house and get ready for dinner.
现在先到我 家里去用晚餐
So you're from Nevada, Mr. Beckwith?
贝克维斯先生 你来自内华达?
Texas, Mama.
是德州 妈妈
Oh, yes. Texas, Mr. Beckwith? Yes, ma'am, Texas.
你是来自德州 贝克维斯先生?
- Benedict's the name. - Oh, yes.
是的 夫人 我叫本尼迪特
- Oh, you're here about the horses, aren't you? - Yes, ma'am.
- 你是来买马的 对吗? - 是的 夫人
I came here to buy your stallion, War Winds.
我想买那匹种马"战风"
That is, if your daughter don't mind too much.
如果你女儿不介意的话
In all likelihood, our Leslie will be leaving us soon in any case.
莱斯莉很可能就要走了
Sir David is with the embassy in Washington...
戴维和大使在华盛顿
...and he's being called back to England.
他被召回英格兰来了
Will she like it there, do you think?
你认为她会喜欢那里吗?
- She's going to marry him? - Well...
- 她要嫁给他? - 呃...
Mother.
妈妈!
Let me sell Mr. Benedict War Winds.
我会把"战风" 卖给本尼迪特先生的
I can tell you all his bad points.
我来告诉你它所有的缺点
For one thing, he eats too much. Doesn't he, Papa?
首先 它吃得很多 对吗 爸爸?
But you see, it's either War Winds or me. Something has to go.
不管是"战风"还是我 都有一个要离开这里
Now, Leslie, you know very well that horse is just too spirited for any woman to ride.
对于女人来说 那匹马太刚烈了
I know, Miss Leslie, that your horse is gonna miss you...
你的马会想念你的
...and all this green country...
还有这个美丽的庄园
...but I'll make him feel right at home in Texas.
可是… 在德州我也会让它幸福的
Isn't Texas green, Mr. Benedict?
德州绿化好吗 本尼迪特先生?
Well, no, ma'am. Not altogether.
不 夫人 并非绿化都很好
You must tell us about Texas, Mr. Benedict.
跟我们说说德州吧
Well, ma'am, it's not that easy. Um...
这可说来话长
It's different than any other state...
它和别的州
...I think.
都不一样
At least that's what we think. But it's almost a different country.
至少我们是这样觉得的 这是完全不同的一个地方
Hmm, from an Englishman's point of view...
从英国人的角度来说
...the mere size of it takes your breath away.
他们一向看重庄园的面积
It's big, all right.
是的 那里确实很大
And how large are your ranches?
你的牧场有多大?
Almost every size. Large, small.
大小都有
Mr. Benedict's Reata is one of the largest of them all.
"利塔"是它们中最大的一个
Oh, really?
真的吗?
Well, just how large is that?
那它有多大?
Oh, it's one of the biggest.
是最大的牧场之一
Hmm. - How big is that?
它到底有多大?
Well, there's one or two others as big, I suppose, up where we come from.
是其它牧场的一到两倍 从我们来的那地方…
One or two others a bit larger down on the coastal plains.
相当于几个 较大的海岸草原
Heh. But come, now, Mr. Benedict, can't you be more specific?
你能说得具体一点吗?
Well, what's the size of your place? Fifty thousand, 20,000 acres?
你的牧场到底有多大? 5万亩 2万亩?
Around a half a million.
五十多万亩
Five hundred and ninety-five thousand acres, to be exact.
具体应该是59.5万亩
Ha, ha. I'd call that quite a parcel.
那真是够大的!
How many acres did you say, Mr. Benedict?
你说的是多少亩 本尼迪特先生?
He said 595,000 acres, Mama.
他说的是59.5万亩
And you should see the greedy look on your face.
你的两眼都放光了 妈妈
Witness excused.
恕我冒昧
Won't you join us at the Hunt Ball, Mr. Benedict? I'm sure you'll enjoy it.
本尼迪特先生 一起来参加我们的舞会吧? 你一定会喜欢的
Oh, no, thank you anyhow, Miss Leslie.
不了 谢谢你 莱斯莉小姐
- I'm afraid I'd look good there in this outfit.   Ha, ha.
恐怕我的 这身衣服不大适合
I like your country.
我喜欢你们的庄园
Why don't you stay on a while, really see something of it?
那为何不多呆一会儿 仔细再看看这里?
Roundup time in my country. Big spring roundup.
我庄园的兽群开始迁移了 春天大迁移
Your country?
你的庄园?
Reata.
"利塔"
Your country, my country. Jordan, you make us sound so far apart.
你的庄园 我的庄园 这样说可把我们距离拉远了
Maybe...
或许吧
...you could come out and see it...
你该去那里看看
...when you get a chance.
如果你有机会的话
- Leslie - Leslie, dear.
- 莱斯莉 -莱斯莉,亲爱的
Miss Leslie. Leslie?
莱斯莉小姐
I guess I'll be off real early in the morning, so...
明天一大早我就要离开了 所以…
...goodbye.
再见
I'm really awfully glad you came.
很高兴见到你
And I'm not going to say goodbye to you here in the moonlight.
在这美好的月夜 我是不会和你说再见的
It would just be too touching. Good night.
这样太伤感了 晚安!
Texas.
"德州"
Are you in love with him?
你爱上他了?
Yes, I think so.
我想是的
Now, will you do me a favor and run along to bed?
睡觉去吧 就算帮我个忙好吗?
- Leslie? - Good night.
-莱斯莉? -晚安
If you're not going to marry David Karfrey...
如果你不和 戴维结婚的话…
...will you give him to me?
可以把他让给我吗?
Yes. Now, good night.
好的!晚安
As far as I'm concerned, Dr. Lynnton, it's a deal.
我所关心的是 这是笔交易
- Ten thousand dollars is a lot of money. - He sure is a lot of horse.
- 一万美金可是个大数目 - 也可以买很多匹马
Let's have some breakfast and get going.
我们用完早餐后再继续吧
Hello.
你好
- Why, Leslie. - Good morning.
- 莱斯莉! - 早上好
Good morning.
早上好
Well, you don't look as if you've been dancing all night, Miss Leslie.
你似乎并没有整晚跳舞 莱斯莉小姐
I came home at a quarter to 11.
我昨晚10:45回家
And I read about Texas until 5 this morning.
然后看那本"德州" 看到早上五点
Oh, Leslie, let the poor boy eat his breakfast in peace.
先让他先用完早餐再说
Ma'am, that takes a heap of reading, Texas does.
那本"德州"里面 有很多内容
We really stole Texas, didn't we, Mr. Benedict?
德州是被我们偷来的 对吗?
I mean, away from Mexico.
我是指 从墨西哥偷来的
You're catching me a bit early to start joking.
一大早你就来 跟我开这种玩笑
But I'm not joking,Jordan.
我没在说笑 乔丹
It's all there in the history books, isn't it?
历史书上都是这么说的
This man, Mr. Austin, came down with about 300 families, it says.
书上说 奥斯丁和 他的三百个家人先到了那里
The next thing you know, they're up and claiming it from Mexico.
接着 他们就把 它从墨西哥夺来了
But, Leslie...
等下 莱斯莉
Why, I never heard anything as ignorant...
我从不相信一些 无知东方人所说的话
Oh, please, Jordan.
行了 乔丹
I'm speaking impersonally, about history.
我只是在客观地 谈论历史而已
You all think that the glory happened here in the East...
你们都认为 这一荣誉只在东部…
- ...with Valley Forge and Bunker Hill. Oh, Jordan...
威利.弗吉和 本克.希尔也是如此!
Do you know about San Jacinto? Have you heard about the Alamo?
你听说过圣.贾辛托 和阿拉莫吗?
Well, certainly.
当然
I read about them all last night.
昨晚我都看过他们的历史
I didn't mean to be impolite. But it's so new to me.
我并非有意无礼 但这些对于我实在太新奇了
I just mean... It's just all so new.
我是说 所有一切 都是那么的新奇…
And so fascinating.
那么的吸引人!
Leslie, you mustn't talk that way to a Texan. They feel very strongly about their state.
你不能这样跟德州人说话 他们对德州都有着很强烈情感
He shouldn't take it so hard.
他也不必这么认真
Jordan, you would think somebody had spoiled you terribly.
乔丹 你一定是受惯了 别人的体贴和宠爱
Your wife or something.
你妻子或者别的人
I haven't any wife. I live with my sister.
我没有妻子 我和姐姐一起生活
Why aren't you married, Jordan?
你为何没结婚呢?
Leslie, first you attack a man's country, and now you try to pry into his family life.
你刚刚冒犯了人家 现在又打听别人的私生活
Thank you, doctor.
谢谢你 医生
- Good morning. - Good morning.
-早上好 -早上好
- Good morning, Lacey. - Good morning, Papa.
-早上好 蕾茜 -早上好 爸爸
How are we doing?
怎么样?
We'll have to be getting along soon, Jordan, if you're going to make your train.
我们得快点了 否则就要错过火车了
- Well, good morning, everybody. - Good morning, Nancy.
-早上好 各位 -早上好 南茜
Good morning, dear. Good morning, Mr. Benedict.
早上好 亲爱的 早上好 本尼迪特先生
Oh, isn't it a beautiful morning?
今天天气真好啊!
Leslie, if Mr. Benedict has finished his breakfast...
莱斯莉 一会儿本尼迪特先生 吃完早餐…
...why don't you show him the stables?
为何不带他到 马棚去参观一下?
We have just quarreled in a polite way about Texas.
我们刚争论完德州的历史
- There's no use trying to pawn me off on him. - Oh.
即使把我典当给他 恐怕也无济于事了
And anyway, Mother, Mr. Benedict is probably engaged to marry...
不过 妈妈… 他或许已经和他附近
...the daughter at the adjoining ranch...
大牧场主的女儿订婚了
...who, though beautiful, is comparatively poor...
她也很漂亮 只不过比不上他有钱而已
...and only has 200,000 acres and half a million cows.
她的牧场只有二十万亩 和五十万头牛而已
Is she, um, pretty?
她漂亮吗?
Ma'am?
女士
We must hurry.
我们得赶紧上路了
Mr. Benedict and I will have to be leaving now.
本尼迪特先生现在得走了
Goodbye, everybody.
再见 所有人
Benedict.
本尼迪特
Who, may I ask, is the lucky young lady that you're going to marry?
我可以问一下 那个有那么多牛的 幸运小姐…
With all those cows.
是哪一位啊?
Benedict.
本尼迪特
I'll get the car.
我去把车开来
- Funny thing, ma'am. - Yes?
太滑稽了 夫人
- My neighbor is a girl. - Oh?
我的邻居只是个女孩
- Vashti Hake. - Hmm.
她叫瓦斯塔.海克
Maybe there was some talk of my marrying her, but I'm not.
人们也曾说过类似的话 但我是不会娶她的
Come along, Benedict, if you want to catch that train.
快点 不然就赶不上火车了
Oh. It all sounds so romantic.
听起来真浪漫!
Come along, David.
戴维
You're for me.
陪陪我吧
What's that, a wolf?
那是什么 狼吗?
No, honey.
不 亲爱的
Just a little old coyote.
只是只小山狗而已
Don't you think you've done enough sightseeing for a while?
还没看够外面的风景吗?
Tell me as soon as we're in Texas.
到德州后好好跟我说说
That's Texas you been looking at, honey.
你刚才看的就是德州
For the last eight hours.
八小时前就到德州了
I don't know how other brides feel on their honeymoon, Mr. Benedict, sir...
我不知道其他 新娘的蜜月之旅感受如何
...but I'm having a lovely time.
但我真的很开心
You can't say it's been dull, honey.
现在还不会觉得乏味
That is, um, so far, anyway.
至少目前是这样
Wake up, honey. We're here, honey.
醒醒 亲爱的 我们到了
We're where?
到哪儿了?
Hello.
你好
Good morning.
早上好
Is that Texas?
这里就是德州?
It's Benedict, honey. It's where we ship from.
这是本尼迪特牧场 也就是我们要去的地方
These people never learn.
这些人从来都学不聪明!
I'm Mrs. Benedict.
我是本尼迪特太太
That means "Welcome the newlyweds." Gracias, Angel.
那是指"欢迎归来 新婚夫妇"  谢谢 安吉尔
Oh. Gracias. Gracias, gracias.
噢 谢谢
Let's go, Leslie.
走吧 莱斯莉
And what is your name?
你叫什么名字?
Angel. Angel Obregon.
安吉尔 安吉尔 奥夫雷贡
Oh, my, that's a beautiful name. Gracias, Angel Obregon.
这名字真好听
Come on, Leslie, it's 50 miles to coffee.
好了 还有五十公里的路要走呢
This is it, honey. This is your home.
到了 亲爱的 这就是你的家
But it's huge.
但是它太大了!
I thought it was a ranch house.
我还以为是一间平房而已
My old man built it to show the cotton crowd...
这房子是我的祖先建的
...that cattlemen were just as high-powered as they were.
让那些柔弱的人 看看我们有多能干
Why, it's enormous, just for two of us.
就我们俩住似乎太大了
Luz lives here with me.
卢斯和我一起住
With us.
和我们一起住
She's run the house ever since Ma passed on.
妈妈去世后就由她照看这房子
Some say she even runs the ranch.
也可以说由她照看这个牧场
Gracias. Gracias.
谢谢
Take it easy, Leslie.
别紧张 莱斯莉
- What are your names? Lupe.
你们叫什么名字?
Petra, senora. - Lupe Petra
佩特拉 女士 -卢佩 佩特拉
- Gracias, Lupe. Gracias, Petra. Gracias, senora.
- 谢谢 卢佩 谢谢 佩特拉 -谢谢 女士
Leslie.
莱斯莉
- You can't behave like that. - What do you mean, behave?
- 你这样做可不行 - 什么意思?
Down here, making a fuss over those people.
对他们无需讲究那么多礼节
You're a Texan now.
你现在是个德州人了
Well, is that a state of mind?
那也是一种思想吗?
I'm still myself.
我还是我自己
You're my wife, honey.
你是我妻子 亲爱的
You're a Benedict.
你是本尼迪特夫人
I still have a mind of my own.
我有自己的想法.
Elsewhere, being gracious is acceptable.
无论到哪儿 礼貌待人是很重要的
We're gracious, but...
我们是要礼貌待人 但是…
Fine thing, standing here quarreling...
好了… 别在这里争论
...the rice still in our hair.
这些鸡毛蒜皮的小事了!
Oh, it's so nice and cool.
感觉真是太棒了!
Luz. Heh.
卢斯 嘿
I thought somebody was hurt.
我还以为有人受伤了
We, uh, didn't know you was there.
我们不知道你在那里
Well, we're home. We're here.
终于到家了
Been looking for you for weeks.
我找了你几个星期了
We weren't expected to be back sooner, were we?
我们是不是回来晚了?
Well, with all this spring work to be done. Roundup.
春天有很多活儿要做 比如牲畜的迁移…
I didn't figure Bick would stay away.
我没想到毕克会外出
Well, if I miss roundup every time I have a honeymoon...
幸好还有这次蜜月
- ...I wouldn't be missing much, would I? Ha, ha.
所以我并没有错过太多 对吗?
I thought I fired him off this place.
我还以为已经把他解雇了呢
Hey, Jett.
嘿 杰特
Where do you think you're going with my automobile?
你要开着我的车到哪儿去?
Just hold on.
别紧张
Don't go taking off on me.
别责怪我
That old truck broke down again. Just simmer down.
那辆老掉牙的卡车又坏了
You want me going down the road?
你想让我走人是吗?
That's exactly what I was gonna do.
我也正求之不得
But she said to me, "You stay on here and do your work."
但她说"你留下来 干完自己的活儿吧"
Next time I tell you to get, you get.
下回我要你来的时候 你才可以来!
Jordan and Jett are everlasting jangling about something. Excuse me.
毕克和杰特老是这样斗嘴
Tell Madama. She's the one that told it to me.
可是玛塔玛让我留下来的
That's right.
没错
With you away, we needed the help.
你一走 我们这里人手就不够了
You know how scared they are of her. They're scared to death of her.
大家都很害怕她
You know that.
这你也知道的
Every one of them except me and you.
我和你除外
You just tend to your work. - Tell me who's the boss around here.
去做你自己的活儿去吧 告诉我 谁才是这里的主人…
I'll be glad to do anything they want me to do. Just tell me who's the boss and, uh...
我会很乐意为你做一切事情的 你只需告诉我谁是这儿的主人
Jett, this is Bick's new wife.
这是毕克的妻子
Leslie, this boy here is Jett Rink.
莱斯莉 他叫杰特.林克
- Hello. Works for us.
-你好 -他为我们工作的
You'd better get going, Jett. Get that truck fixed.
你最好赶紧走 杰特 去把那辆卡车修好
Ain't nobody king in this country.
这个庄园里 没人可以自称国王
Ain't nobody, no matter what they might be thinking.
任何人都不可以
Sorry, honey.
对不起 亲爱的
Things go loco around here every time I'm away.
每回我一离开 这里就会出乱子
Remember the time at the big rodeo? Yeah.
还记得 那次牛仔竞技比赛吗?
Old Kale Beebe blew in higher than a kite...
老凯利来了 就是那个高个子
...slept on the sofa down there in Bick's office.
在你办公室的沙发上睡着了
He must've rode nightmares all night.
那晚他一定在做恶梦
He cut the couch to ribbons with his spurs.
沙发都被他用马鞭抽烂了
This here is Bick's room.
这是毕克的房间
This down here is your room, honey.
你的房间在楼下 亲爱的
Ha, ha. - Ha, ha. Look, uh...
呃…
Luz, uh, we're married.
我们结婚了
Well, you know how that is.
你知道的
We, uh...
我们 额
We'll take these two connecting rooms here.
我们要住一间套房那里
Make that into a sitting room where we can sort of sit and talk...
我们想把那间房作为起居室 坐在那儿聊天
...where the breeze can get at us.
还可享受阵阵微风
Howdy. - Oh.
你好
Petra's got your breakfast ready.
佩特拉把早餐准备好了
You and Jordan have had breakfast already?
你和乔丹都用过早餐了?
Sure, Bick and me, we have our coffee and talk every morning of our lives at 5:00.
每天早上五点 我们都会喝着咖啡聊天的
Trying to get things rounded up for the day.
把每天的事情都安排好
I thought I was going riding with him to the roundup.
我还以为会和 他一起去驱赶畜群
It would have been too hot for you. I told him so.
天气对于你来说太热了 我也跟他说过
Petra, bring it in here.
佩特拉 把早餐拿过来
You gotta watch out for that sun. It's rough.
这里的太阳很毒 你最好小心一点
Sit down.
坐吧
Your blood's too thin. That's the trouble with a lot of Easterners.
看你细皮嫩肉的 东方人就是麻烦
Thank you, Petra. Gracias. Gracias.
谢谢 佩特拉
Oh, I'm fine, Luz.
我很好 卢斯
I'm a lot tougher, perhaps, than you think I am.
或许我没你想象中 那么弱不经风
Me...
我…
...I never had a sick day in my life.
我一生中都没生过病
Except when I got throwed and tromped on.
哪怕是从马背摔下来
All you gotta do is take it easy.
你也不要太过紧张
This rich Texas air will fix you up.
我们会为你安排好一切的
And don't you worry none about being lonesome.
你也别担心在这里会寂寞
I'm gonna round up the neighbors.
我会把邻居们都叫出来
You're gonna meet some folks. Yes, indeedy.
让你跟他们见见面 是的
You're gonna meet some folks.
你会跟他们都见面的
This is Mr. and Mrs. Bale Clinch.
这是贝尔.克林夫妇
- Bick, it's about time. Howdy, Bale.
真有你的 毕克.您好
Howdy, ma'am. I'd like you to meet my wife, Adarene.
这是我妻子 阿德雷妮
I'm mighty pleased to meet you.
很高兴见到你
- Howdy, Adarene. - Howdy, Bick.
- 你好 阿德雷妮 -你好 毕克
This is our Judge Whiteside.
这是怀特赛德
How do you do? We sure are proud to have you here.
你好吗 本尼迪特太太? 很荣幸你到这儿来
Bick, congratulations.
毕克 恭喜你
- Might happy for you, boy. She sure is pretty. - I think so.
- 你真走运 伙计 她真的很漂亮 - 是的
- Eula Japes. - Glad to meet you, ma'am.
- 这是乌拉.杰佩斯  - 很高兴见到你
Howdy. - Good to see you.
很高兴见到你 毕克
- This is Miss Wortan. - Howdy, Leslie. I'm mighty happy to meet you.
- 这是沃顿小姐  - 你好 莱斯莉 很高兴见到你
Howdy. Hello, Bick.
早上好 你好 毕克
And Fernie Clang. - Miss Leslie, we're so glad to have you with us.
这是菲尼.克林 欢迎你的到来
- You've really done well for yourself. - Thank you, Fernie.
- 你会生活得很愉快的 - 谢谢你 菲尼
Hey, Fernie.
嘿 菲尼
Leslie
莱斯莉
You're gonna meet the neighbor I told you about.
现在来见见 我跟你提到过的邻居
My next-door neighbor?
我的邻居
Only lives 50 miles from here, with all those cows?
就是住在五十公里外 有很多牛群的那位?
Vashti.
瓦斯塔
I'd like you to meet my wife.
我想向你介绍我妻子
Hello, Vashti. So nice to meet you.
你好 瓦斯塔 很高兴见到你
Jordan's told me so much about you.
乔丹跟我说了 很多关于你的事情
Mighty glad to know you, Mrs. Jordan Benedict.
很高兴能认识你
I'm awfully glad we're neighbors. And I hope we'll be real close friends.
很高兴我们成为邻居 希望我们能成为好朋友
- Hi, Bick. Well, howdy, Pinky.
嗨 毕克 早上好 宾奇
Hello, Mrs. Benedict.
你好 本尼迪特太太
My name is Mort Snythe. They call me Pinky.
我叫莫特.辛 他们都叫我"宾奇"
- Bick. Yeah?
毕克 嗯?
You, Bick. Come here.
快过来
What do you want?
怎么了
Excuse me, ma'am.
失陪了 夫人
- We'll be seeing you. All right.
-我们会来拜访你的
- This will perk you up. Oh, thank you.
-这会让你兴奋的 莱斯莉小姐 -谢谢
Folks, I propose a toast to a daughter of old Maryland...
我想敬这位 老马里兰的女儿…
...that's blooming into a citizen of the Lone Star State.
成为德州的一员
- To the bride. To the bride.
敬这位新娘!
- You all right, honey? - Oh, I'm fine, thank you.
你没事吧? 别担心 我没事
There's more than one bride here today.
-今天在这儿的不只一位新娘
How's that, Vashti?
-何以见得 瓦斯塔?
Mort Snythe and I were married yesterday in Hermosa.
莫特和我昨天刚在 "赫莫沙"结婚了
Leave the boy alone. I want to kiss him.
我要亲吻他!
- I guess that leaves only me. - Aw, Luz.
现在就只剩下我了
Why, everybody in the county knows you'd rather herd cattle than make love.
卢斯 大伙儿认为 你赶牲畜的功夫比做爱强!
Yeah, well, one thing you gotta say for cattle.
对于牲畜你们 要记住一件事
Boy, you put your brand on one of them, you're gonna know where it's at.
把你的记号烙在它们身上 这样就不会丢了!
Come and get it!
快过来吃东西吧!
Or I'll throw it in the creek.
或者我要把它扔进溪里
It's the best food you ever ate, honey.
这是你从未 吃过的最好的东西 亲爱的
It's real Mexican barbacoa.
这是地道的墨西哥烤味
It's where we get the word "barbecue."
也就是我们所说的"烧烤"
What is that?
那是什么?
Calf's head.
小牛的头
We take it and wrap it in clean white cloth...
我们首先用白布把它包裹
...and then wrap it tight in canvas...
再用帆布包紧
...and put it down in a pit of hot mesquite coals.
然后放到坑里用
It stays down there 18 hours, and boy, them brains are sure sweet.
炭火熏上18个小时 那些脑髓最美味的了!
How fascinating.
太棒了!
Honey, I don't think I'm really terribly hungry.
我现在并不饿
It must be the heat.
可能是天气热的原因
You call this hot?
这样就叫热吗?
Wait till July.
七月那时才真正热呢!
Eat it while it's hot.
趁热吃吧!
What's the matter with her?
她怎么了 毕克?
That's what I was afraid of.
这正是我担心的!
Leslie?
莱斯莉!
Good morning, Luz.
早上好 卢斯
What you doing up?
你在这儿干什么?
Getting breakfast.
做早餐
Look, Luz.
嘿 卢斯
I think there's something that we should get in the clear and in the open.
我想有些事情 我们应该说清楚
I don't want to take your place. I want you to know that.
我并不想霸占你的地方 这点我想让你知道
But I can't have you taking my place either.
但我也不想让你霸占我的
I can't be just a guest in my husband's house.
我不想只作为 我丈夫家里的一个客人
There you are. - Good morning, darling.
你在这儿呢 早上好 亲爱的
- How do you feel? Fine.
-你感觉怎么样了? -很好
Ah, you look fine.
你气色还不错
I want everybody to know, no matter what happens around this ranch in the future...
我想让大家都知道 无论以后发生什么事情
...I am never going to faint again.
我都不会再晕倒了
Well...
好吧
...I'll never get the hang of you, Mrs. Benedict.
我也决不会再扶你了 本尼迪特太太
Horse like that, that cost you a lot of money...
这匹种马你可是花了很多钱的
...I'd use for breeding.
我还要拿它来配种
I wouldn't let anybody ride him. I don't care if she's your wife or who she is.
我不想让任何人骑它 即使是你妻子也不行
Bick, I'd see she rides a more gentle animal if I was you.
要是我就让她 骑一匹温顺点的马
She's gonna fall off and break her neck.
她会把脖子给摔断的
That's Old Polo.
那是老保罗
He's head vaquero.
是牧牛人的头儿
He's been here longer than any of us, I guess...
他比这儿的时间 比我们任何人都长
...since Grandpa Benedict's time.
我爷爷那时候 他一直就在这儿
Look at them, honey.
看啊 亲爱的!
There's never been anything like them in this world, I can tell you.
我敢跟你说 世界上不会再看到这种景象了
Did you ever see such stock?
你见过如此多的牛群吗?
- Are they all ours? Yeah.
它们都是我们的?
These and 49,000 others just like them.
这些和其它49 000头牛 都是我们的
Granddaddy and his boys used to drive his longhorns...
我爷爷和他的伙计过去 把这些长角牛…
...right through here, all the way to Kansas.
一路从堪萨斯赶到了这里
- Imagine. - Yeah.
想象一下 -是啊
Yeah, he was a pretty good old boy. I mean, he was tough too.
他很能干.他也很强壮
My old man brought stock from Europe and bred them to the best we had.
我的祖辈从欧洲买来种马 然后好好喂养它们
Look out, you loco...
小心!
This right here is the result, honey.
于是才有今天的这一切 亲爱的
Look at them.
看啊
How you doing?
你怎么了?
- Tired, huh? - Now, don't you worry about me.
累了吗? 别为我担心
I'm a tough Texan now.
我是个坚强的德州人
You know I love you, Tex.
我爱你
Hello, Luz.
你好 卢斯
Hi, everybody.
你们好
Jett, hold on a minute.
等一下 杰特
I want you to take Mrs. Benedict back in with you.
让本尼迪特太太和你一起回去
- Honey, you go along with Jett. Honey, I'm fine, really.
和杰特回去 这里太热了 亲爱的 我没事 真的
There's no use overdoing it. Go along with Jett.
没必要勉强自己 和杰特回去吧
Good morning, Jett.
早上好 杰特
You take it easy, Jett.
小心点 杰特
I don't want to chew on this, Bick...
本来我不想说的 毕克…
...but I think we'd better get it straight.
但我想最好还是说清楚的好
I run the house, don't I?
这家归我管 对吗?
Her house, her kitchen, her help.
她的房子 厨房 庸人
- She don't even speak Spanish. - Oh, they understand plenty English.
她甚至不会说西班牙语 庸人们迟早会懂得英语的
I know how to handle Mexicans.
我懂得怎样跟墨西哥人打交道
Doing it all my life.
我一辈子都在做这个
They'd sit on their honkers all day...
他们就会整天喝得烂醉
- ...if I didn't keep after them. - All right, Luz. Cool off.
如果我不盯紧他们的话 好了 卢斯 冷静点
Well, I thought we ought to talk without her around.
我们最好趁她 不在的时候好好谈谈
I just don't want to feel that you're setting up against me, Bick.
我不想有种被 你欺骗的感觉 毕克
Nobody is setting up against you, Luz.
没人欺骗你 卢斯
That gal is my wife.
那女孩是我的妻子
And you're fair enough, I think...
我想你也是很公平的
...to try and get along with her.
好好跟她相处吧
All right, I...
好吧
I'll catch me up a horse and help push the stock along for a while.
我还是找匹马来遛遛吧
- Maybe it'll make me feel better. - All right.
或许这样会让我好受些
If you gotta push something.
随你怎么遛好了
When I get enough, I'll ride on in.
我走累的时候 我会骑上去的
Why did you come to Texas?
你为何到德州来?
Well, I mean, seems like everybody else is trying to get away from here.
大伙儿都想着要离开这里
Me, I'm gonna get out of here one of these days.
或许过几天 我也要离开这里了
This is my husband's land.
这是我丈夫的土地
This is his home.
这是他的家
Who gets ahold of this much land unless they took it off somebody else?
谁能有那么多的土地? 除非他们是从别人那里夺过来的
You're not exactly loyal to your employer, are you, Jett?
你对你的老板确实 很不忠诚 杰特
No, sir, I'm not complaining. I'm not complaining.
不 我并没有抱怨
They bought this land long ago.
这块土地是他们 很久前就买下来的
Benedicts.
本尼迪特家族
- They got it through purchase years ago. - They took it off a bunch of Mexicans.
-这是他们很多年之前买的 -从无知的墨西哥人那里买的
Why, that's not true, Jett.
这不对
They bought and traded for Spanish land grants.
这土地是得到 西班牙允许后
Paid for it, all right.
才买下的
They paid 5 cents an acre.
他们是以 每亩5美分的价格买下的
I know my folks is here in Texas long enough to get rich too.
我的祖辈呆在 这里也变得富有了
Except they just weren't so foxy.
只不过他们没那么狡猾罢了
Leave it on, boy. I'll ride him.
给我 我来骑它
Nobody ride him but the senora.
除了太太之外没人骑得了它
Been riding what I want to here for 30 years.
我在马背上已经三十多年了
He buck off Lopez.
它刚把洛佩斯摔下来
If he bucks me down, he won't be the first one that's done it.
它要能把我摔下来 它也不是第一匹把我摔下来的马
I suppose you came out here to show me how to run things too.
我倒也想看看你有什么能耐
Let's go.
走
Now, I'm not too awful bad now.
我现在并不很糟
I got a few friends.
我也有几个朋友
Madama likes me.
玛塔玛也喜欢我
And old Bick, now even old Bick...
毕克 他也
...he likes me...
开始有点
...a little bit.
喜欢我了
Well, now, but they don't like me...
当然 他们并没那么
...quite enough...
喜欢我…
...to kind of divvy up what they got way too much of.
只不过是想 从中多得一点而已
You are an odd one, aren't you, Jett?
你真是个奇怪的人 杰特.
But I like you.
但我喜欢你
I like you too.
我也喜欢你
I guess you're about the best-looking gal we've seen around here in a long time.
你是我们在这里 见过的最漂亮的女孩
I think...
也是我来这以后
...the prettiest one...
见过的
...I think I've seen down here.
最漂亮的女孩
Why, thank you, Jett.
谢谢你 杰特
That's a very nice compliment.
你可真会奉承
And I'm gonna tell my husband of that, with your approval.
可以的话 我想把这话告诉我丈夫
Oh, well, now, I...
不
I wouldn't do that. Well...
我不会再这样说了
No, I...
不 我
No, I wouldn't do that.
我不会再说了
Beautiful Reata. Tsk.
美丽的"利塔"!
Them's your neighbors live there.
他们是你的邻居
- Who? Them kids there.
那些小孩
Them's your ranch people.
都是你牧场工人的孩子
Them's Angel Obregon's kids.
他们是安吉尔的孩子
That's the man that met us at the train.
那人我们在火车旁遇见过
They're sure in good shape, ain't they? Whole bunch of them sick.
他们很"健康" 对吗? 他们全都病了
- What's the matter with them? - I don't know, just sick.
他们到底怎么了? 我不知道
Every one of them.
只是全都病了而已
Wait a minute. I want to get out here.
等等 我想出去
Well, I wouldn't do that if I was you.
换成是我不会那样做的
Wait.
等等
You are the boss. And you know it too, don't you?
你是老板 你知道这事的 对吗?
- May I come in? Enter.
我可以进来吗?
I'm Mrs. Benedict.
我是本尼迪特太太
Perdoname...
我叫佩多纳姆
...that I do not rise.
我无法起床
The baby is sick.
孩子病了
My milk is not good.
我的奶水不好
Poor darling.
亲爱的
Have you seen a doctor?
你去看大夫了吗?
Doctor...
大夫?
He is too far to come.
离这里太远了
Say, Miss Leslie? I think we better be getting on.
莱斯莉夫人 我们该走了
This baby is extremely ill.
这孩子病得很重
Well, you're not supposed to be in there. It's...
你不该到这儿来的
Try not to worry, Mrs. Obregon.
别担心 欧布雷夫人
I'll be back soon.
我很快就回来
Old Bick's gonna blow a gasket.
毕克会生气的
What is it?
怎么了?
What's happened to him?
它怎么了?
What's wrong?
发生什么事了?
Where in the world have you been?
你到哪儿去了?
Good Lord, I've been looking for you too.
我一直在找你
What happened to her?
她怎么了?
We stopped by the village.
我刚才经过了村子
What happened?
怎么了?
Just awful.
太可怕了
I don't know. She was...
我也不知道 她
...riding War Winds.
骑着"战风"出去
She got thrown or something.
或许是从马背上摔下来了
What does the doctor say?
大夫怎么说?
Bad.
情况很糟
She hit her head on a mesquite stump.
她的头撞到了树桩上
She's been riding since she was 6.
她六岁就开始骑马
She could ride anything. And now this happens.
她可以骑任何马 没想到发生这种事
How is she?
她怎么样了?
She's in a state of shock.
她摔得很严重 非常严重
Very serious. Concussion, possible hemorrhage.
脑部受到震荡 内出血了
I'm doing all I can do.
我已经尽力了
I called Dr. Borneholm, got him on the phone.
我已经给 伯内霍姆大夫打电话了
He ought to be along any minute now.
他很快就赶过来
Doctor?
医生
If I only hadn't bought that horse.
要是我没买那匹马就好了
Don't blame yourself, Jordan.
别自责了 乔丹
If I hadn't, she'd be alive right now.
要是我没买的话 她就不会死
Don't blame yourself.
别再自责了
This is a great misfortune...
这件事很不幸
...but no one's to blame.
但没人该受到责怪
Yeah.
是啊
Things happen.
事情已经发生了
Dr. Walker? - Mrs. Benedict, this is Dr. Borneholm.
-本尼迪特太太 这是伯内霍姆大夫
How do you do?
-你好
Bick, I sure wish I could have made it for Luz.
我很希望能救活卢斯
Dr. Walker did everything he could, I assure you of that.
沃克大夫已经尽力了 这点我可以向你保证
I know. Thank you.
我知道 谢谢你
Dr. Walker, there's more for you to do, I'm afraid.
沃克大夫 恐怕还有些事情要你帮忙
Mrs. Obregon's baby is very sick.
欧布雷夫人的孩子 病得很重
His temperature must be at least 105.
他的体温至少在105度
Will you stop by, please?
你可以去看一下吗?
Mrs. Obregon?
欧布雷太太?
In the village.
就在村子那里
Jett will take you.
杰特会带你去的
I'll go with you myself, doctor.
我和你一起去吧 大夫
Leslie.
莱斯莉
What is this?
这怎么回事?
He can't do that.
你不能这样
He can't go there.
他不能到那儿去
He's our doctor.
他是我们的大夫
- Our doctor? - Yeah.
-我们的大夫 -是的
You mean the Benedicts' only?
你是说 只是本尼迪特家的大夫?
No, I mean...
不 我是说
...all of us.
我们所有人的大夫
He don't tend those people.
他不能给那些人看病
They...
他们
...have a way of doing things by themself.
能够自己想办法的
How'd she get there, Jett?
她怎么到那儿去的?
Oh, don't go climbing onto me.
别又拿我开刀
I don't feel none too good about it.
我也不想这样的
Jordan, darling, I don't think you quite understand.
乔丹 亲爱的 我想你还不明白
There's a child who's very sick.
有个孩子病得很重
I must take Dr. Walker.
我必须带沃克大夫去
You'll go, won't you, doctor?
你会去的 对吗 大夫?
I'll be back just as soon as I can, darling.
我会尽快回来的
I'm a lot better, honey.
我现在好多了 亲爱的
That's a good boy.
这就好
Where's my horse?
我的马呢?
I shot him.
我向它开枪了
Bone was broken.
它的骨头断了
Somebody had to do it.
必须有人这样做
Thought it'd be better if it was me.
我想最好还是由我来做吧
The baby?
孩子怎么样了?
Alive.
活下来了
Thanks to Dr. Walker.
多亏了沃特大夫
Good.
那就好
Bick.
毕克
Excuse me, but we've gotta have you in here for a few minutes, if you can break away.
我们这里有些事情 想和你谈谈
Jordan.
乔丹
Say, Bick, you're sure holding up fine.
你很快就好挺过去的
It's times like this that folks really show what they're made of, and you're holding up fine.
这时刻才真正能 表现出一个人的坚强
- Mrs. Benedict, bye-bye. Oh, goodbye.
本尼迪特太太 再见
Vern and me thought a lot of Luz, Mrs. Benedict.
维恩和我会想念卢斯的
But I guess everybody did.
大伙儿都会想念她的
Yeah, at least everybody came.
至少大伙儿都来了
Biggest gathering for a funeral I ever saw in Texas.
这是我在德州 见过的最盛大的葬礼了
Mm. Shame Luz wasn't here to enjoy it.
只可惜卢斯没能到场
Well, I mean, she always did like a big get-together and everything. Heh.
我是说 她一直都很喜欢盛大的聚会
She'd have had a fine time.
她该生活得很幸福的
- Well, bye. - Goodbye.
好 再见
- Come see us. - Thank you, bye-bye. Come see us.
-常来看我们 -谢谢你们 再见 常来看我们
Jordan...
乔丹
...I think you'll agree with me that your sister was a very generous woman.
你姐姐是一个 非常慷慨的人
She wanted that boy to have something...
她想给那个人 一些
...something worthwhile.
值钱的东西
Now that little piece of land is worth, oh, 5-... ...600 dollars at most.
也就是一小块价值… 500到600美元的土地
I'm going to ask you, in reverence to the memory of Luz Benedict...
我想问你 出于对卢斯.本尼迪特的尊敬
...I'm going to ask you to give one Jett Rink...
你要给杰特.林克…
...a check for twice the value of that land.
一张相当于那块 土地两倍价值的支票
We can clean up the whole matter right now.
现在就开始着手这件事吧
Jett, come on inside. I want to talk to you.
进来 我有事情跟你说
Now, just a minute here, Bick.
等等 毕克
Afraid I'm gonna beat you to it.
恐怕这次我恕难从命了
I'm quitting.
我不干了
I lost the one friend I had in this place, and I know it too.
在这儿我 已经失去了一个朋友
So I quit. I'm dead quit. Don't have to say another word to me.
我不干了 你不必再跟我说什么
Nobody's firing you, Jett.
没人要解雇你
Boy, howdy, nobody's firing me.
是的 没人要解雇我
I told you, I quit.
我告诉你 我不干了!
Nobody wants to fire you.
没人想解雇你
Now, just come on inside and listen to what we have to say.
进来跟我们商量一些事情
Come on in here, Jett. Come on in here, boy. Heh.
快进来 杰特
- Hi, Jett. Nice to see you. Hi.
杰特 很高兴见到你
- Howdy. Good to see you. - Howdy.
-你好 杰特 很高兴见到你 -你好 杰特
Have my seat here, boy. Sit right down. Sure looking good today.
请坐 伙计 你今天气色很不错啊
Sit down, Jett. Gonna tell you about a little piece of luck's come your way.
坐吧 我要告诉你 一件让你兴奋的事情
Sit down, young man, sit down and make yourself comfortable.
坐吧 年轻人 别拘谨
It's a real bad wind that doesn't blow somebody some good.
有的人是 好运挡也挡不住啊
Amen.
阿门
Jett, I don't guess I have to tell you... ...Luz was a woman of strong sentimental feeling.
卢斯是一个坚强 又很富有感情的人 这点我无需多说
She prepared a list of things that she wanted to give the people on Reata.
她把要送给"利塔" 所有人的东西都列出来了
Yes, we find that she wanted to... Heh. Well, that is...
是的 她想要给…
...we find that her bequest to you is in the nature of a little piece of ground.
她给你遗赠的是 这里的一小块土地
It's that little piece we used to call "Buffalo Wallow."
也就是"水牛坛" 那一小块土地
Now...
现在
She wanted to give you something. I know she did.
她想给你东西 我也知道她会的
It's always been my aim to kind of keep Reata intact, within the family.
但保持"利塔"完整无缺 是我一向的目标
Now, that little piece is worth...
这块土地的价值最多是…
...hmm, at the most... How much, Bale?
多少来着 贝尔?
At the most, 5- or 600 dollars, Bick.
最多是500到600美元 毕克
Yes, now, um, Mr. Benedict, wanting to honor his sister's wishes...
本尼迪特先生 遵从他姐姐的遗嘱
...and, of course, right along with his own personal feeling for you...
当然 还有他对你的关爱…
...now, he wants to see to it that you get something really worthwhile.
他想让你的付出 得到更多的回报
Well, now, to get right down to the point, Mr. Rink...
言归正传吧 林克先生
...we're prepared to place in your hands in cash...
我们准备 付给你现金…
...the sum of $1200.
1 200美元
- Yes, sir. Ha, ha. - Boy.
好的 先生 -孩子
Twelve hundred dollars...
1 200美元
...which any of these gentlemen here, I'm sure they'll be happy to tell you...
在座的各位先生都会 很高兴地告诉你…
- ...it's twice the value of that land. Definitely. At least.
这相当于 那块地的两倍价钱
Twice the value of that land.
-没错 -至少是两倍价格
That's a lot of money, Jett.
这可是一大笔钱
What are you aiming to do with all of it?
你拿着它要干些什么呢?
You're in the chips now, boy.
你现在有钱了 伙计
There it is. There it is, boy. Ha, ha.
快拿着吧
- And it's all yours. Ha, ha. Sure is.
这都是你的
I don't know what to say. Ha, ha.
我不知道该说些什么
She was a fine lady.
她人真的是很好
Yes, she was a fine lady. Hallelujah.
是的 她人是很好 哈利路亚!
Amen.
阿门
And I...
我
I want to...
我想要
I want you to know that I appreciate her, uh, generosity.
我很感激她的这份慷慨
And yours too, Bick. And you all.
还有你 毕克 你们在座的各位
I sure do want to thank you for it.
我很感谢你们
You know something, Bick? Ahem.
你知道吗.毕克?
I don't know, but what it just might not be...
我也不知道 但这或许…
...a pretty good idea to gamble along with old Madama.
这种做法或许 不是个好主意
How do you mean?
你是什么意思?
Just gamble along.
自己碰碰运气
Just keep what she give me.
留着她给我的东西
I'm sentimental too, Bick.
我也是有感情的 毕克
I just think that it's good to gamble along with her.
我想最好是留着这块地
I know that land ain't worth much but then, someday...
我知道它不值几个钱 但有一天
...I just might up and put my own fence around her.
我发展起来后 我就会用栅栏把它围起来
Call her "Little Reata."
然后命名为"小利塔"
See you.
再见
There's only one thing more important than money, and that's land.
世上唯一比 金钱重要的东西就是土地
Why, I've heard Luz say it a thousand times.
卢斯已经说过上千遍了
Pa said it, and Bick Benedict says it. And it's true.
毕克也是这么说的 是真的!
You ever get up to Deaf Smith, you come and pay us a visit.
你真该来我们 "史密斯牧场"看一看
We're just on the outside of Umbarger.
我们就在"安巴杰"的另一边
Only a little bitty piece, only we had a run of luck.
那地值不了几个钱 不过我们还算走运
Only? Well, a gusher come in last year.
-还算走运? 去年那里可发现了一口油井
- How wonderful. - Right now it's bringing in a million.
-真是太好了 立刻就带来了上百万
- A million gallons? - Dollars.
-一百万加仑? -美元
- A million dollars a year? - Million dollars a month.
一百万美元一年?
- Oh, a month. - Goodbye.
一百万美元一个月 -再见
- Thanks for treating us right. Thank you for coming.
感谢您的款待 -感谢你们的到来
I just love talking to you, Uncle Bawley.
我很喜欢和你聊天 保莱叔叔
Now that it's over, you get that fellow of yours to take you around and show you our country.
以后 你可以让你的丈夫… 带你去看看我们的国家
See San Antonio... ...Dallas and Houston.
看看圣安东尼奥 达拉斯 还有休斯顿
I'm so impatient. I want to see it all right now.
我都等不及了 我现在就想去看看
You don't have to hurry, honey.
不必那么心急 亲爱的
It'll be here when you get around to it.
你会有时间去看的
Been here a long time.
时间长着呢
And once you see it all, and have lived with it as I have...
当你看完之后 然后像我一样 在这里再生活上…
...well, let's say 25 years from now, you'll feel about Texas just like I do.
二十五年 你就会和我一样了解德州了
- Twenty-five years from now. - Mm-hm.
再过上二十五年!
Twenty-five years from now, I'll be almost 50.
二十五年之后 我就五十岁了
It's a nice age, Leslie.
这可是一个黄金年龄 莱斯莉
You'll see wonderful things in Texas when you're 50.
你五十岁的时候 会看到很多奇妙的事情
Perhaps.
或许吧
But I won't care as much then.
但那时或许 我没那么在乎了
You will care more.
你会在乎的
- Because then... Hey, Bawley. you'll have been part of it all.
因为那时 你已经成为了它的一部分
- Come on, we need you in the powwow. Coming.
快过来 大伙儿都在等着你呢
Judge, how's it shaping up?
法官 这是怎么回事
It's gonna be all right.
一切都会好起来的
You get with it, Gomez.
格梅斯 把你的人都叫走
Get your people out. I don't want them sitting on their honkers come election day.
我可不想在大选日那天 看见他们醉醺醺的坐在那里
Everything will be bueno, senora. It will be the same, good.
一切都会安排妥当的 先生
Goodbye, Gomez.
再见 格梅斯
I love you.
我爱你
Well...
额
...thank you.
谢谢
We're just talking business. Just business.
我们在谈生意而已
Oh, please don't mind me.
别在意我
Do go on.
你们继续
I'll listen quiet as a little old mouse.
我会像一个 小老鼠一样静静地听的
You'd be bored, honey.
亲爱的 你会无聊的
This is dull.
这很无聊的
Why, I'd be fascinated.
怎么 我对这个很感兴趣
Leslie, we're talking about politics.
我们在谈论政治
You married me in Washington, remember, darling?
亲爱的 我们是在 华盛顿结婚的 还记得吗?
I lived next door to politics, brought up with it.
我可是在政治的 熏陶之下成长的
Please do go on talking. I'd love it.
请继续吧 我喜欢听
This is men's stuff.
这是男人的事情
Leslie, how about a cup of coffee or a drink or something?
莱斯莉 来喝杯咖啡或者茶怎么样?
Men's stuff.
男人的事情!
Lord have mercy.
上帝真是仁慈!
Set up my spinning wheel, girls. I'll join the harem section in a minute.
你们快过来 我倒要听听他们说的是什么政治
Now, Leslie.
听着 莱斯莉
Don't you go worrying your pretty little head about politics. Heh, heh.
漂亮的小姐是 不必关心政治的
You mean my pretty, empty head, don't you, judge?
你是指我漂亮而无知 对吗 法官?
Could I get the coffee for you, Leslie?
我给你来杯咖啡好吗?
You too, Uncle Brutus?
你也是这意思吗 布鲁特叔叔?
You don't feel well, Leslie.
或许你身体不舒服 莱斯莉
I feel just great.
我感觉很好!
My adrenaline glands are pumping beautifully.
我的感觉一切良好
If I may say so before retiring...
在走之前我想说的是…
...you gentlemen date back 100,000 years.
你们又回到了十万年前
You ought to be wearing leopard skins and carrying clubs.
你们应该穿着猎豹皮 拿着大棍子
Politics.
政治!
Business.
生意!
What is so masculine...
这个所谓的
...about a conversation that a woman can't enter into it?
男人间的 谈话到底是什么?
Leslie, you're tired.
莱斯莉 你累了
Perhaps I am.
我或许是累了
Judge, I think if you get down in Brewster county and campaign...
法官 我觉得如果你沿布鲁斯特村走下去
Yeah, well...
额 好吧
Pinky, I reckon I'll go on upstairs and get my beauty sleep.
我想我该上楼睡觉去了
You go ahead on, honey.
去吧 亲爱的
Good night, gentlemen.
晚安 先生们
Good night, honey. - Good night, Vashti.
晚安 亲爱的 -晚安 维斯泰
Good night, Vashti.
晚安 维斯泰
That's right, send the children on up to bed...
这下好了 把孩子们打发去睡觉
...so the grown-ups can talk.
这样大人就可以谈话了
- Good night, Leslie. - Night, honey.
晚安 莱斯莉 -晚安 亲爱的
Oh, I must've dropped off.
我一定是太累了
Oh, darling, I am sorry about my caveman speech.
亲爱的 我为刚才 "石器时代的发言"道歉
I'll apologize to the others first thing, I promise.
明天一大早我 就向其他人道歉
That's big of you.
你真够大胆的
- You certainly distinguished yourself. - Shh. They can hear.
今晚你可真的是出尽风头了
Hear? They heard you already. Every word you said out there.
-他们会听见的 -听见?你的话他们都听到了
We date back 100,000 years.
你在那里说的每一句话 我们又回到了十万年前
I said I was sorry about the name-calling.
我都为这件事向你道歉了
It was very impolite, I know.
我也知道 这样很无礼
But in principle, I was absolutely right.
但从原则上讲 我是正确的
You come down here and you try to tell us how to run things...
你来告诉我们做事的原则
...insulting my friends and everything.
让我的朋友脸上无光
Now, you look here, Leslie.
听着 莱斯莉
You're my wife. Mrs. Jordan Benedict.
你是我妻子 是乔丹.本尼迪特太太
I'm asking you, when are you gonna settle down and behave like everybody else?
我问你 你何时才能 像其他女人一样守规矩呢?
Never. - Who do you think you are?
-永远也不! -你以为自己是谁?
Joan of Arc or something?!
是圣女贞德吗?
Jordan, where are you going?
乔丹 你要上哪儿去?
Jordan, take off your hat.
乔丹 把帽子摘下来
Carrying on like Carrie Nation, preaching stuff that's none of your business.
你真是愚蠢之极 谈论政治不是你们的事情
Fixing the world. Why don't you join a club?
你为何不去参加俱乐部?
Honestly, Jordan. You make me sound just awful.
乔丹 你不能这样对我
I'm not all that bad.
我还不至于那么糟
You knew what a frightful girl I was when you married me.
你娶我的时候就知道 我是个很强的女孩
I did not deceive you, sir.
我没有欺骗你
Why, from the very first moment, I couldn't have been more unpleasant.
自始自终 我就没给人不好的感觉
Anyway, you're stuck with me.
再说 你也离不开我
Yeah, I guess.
我想是的
Honey, take your hat off.
亲爱的 把帽子摘掉吧
Besides, you love me very much.
而且… 你深爱着我
Yeah.
是啊
But that fine mind of yours gets pretty repulsive at times.
在火车上的时候
That's not what you told me on the train.
你可不是这样对我说的
Now you're gonna throw that up to me.
现在你又想来责怪我
I thought what we...
我还以为…
I thought what we said on the train was in confidence.
我们在火车上 说的话只有我们知道
Well, of course, darling.
当然 亲爱的
But I'll never forget a single word you said to me.
但我永远不会忘记 你对我说的每一句话的
You know, you can be pretty wonderful at times.
有时候 你可以做得更好的
Come on, partner.
来吧 宝贝
Why don't you kick off your spurs?
为何不把鞋子脱掉?
What a glorious, gorgeous, brand-new day.
真是美丽而崭新的一天!
Let's spend every hour of it just you and I.
享受这每一刻吧 就你和我
Oh, honey, I'm beat.
亲爱的 我很累
Why?
怎么了?
Today you have all the good things in the world...
世上所有 美好的东西你都拥有了
...and a woman who loves you very, very much.
还有一个 深爱着你的女人
I know, but... That arguing takes a lot out of me.
但昨晚那次争吵 让我很难受
Oh, that was just frightful.
那真是太可怕了
Best part about quarreling is the making up.
争吵最好的疗法 就是弥补
When we make up, we make up too, don't we, honey?
我们一起来弥补 好吗 亲爱的?
Why can't we take a trip, really see Texas? Just let somebody else run Reata.
我们为何不去好好看看德州? 让别人来管理"利塔"好了
- Hmm? - Oh, couldn't we?
可以吗?
Honey, I want you to understand this:
亲爱的 你要明白一点
I run Reata at all times.
"利塔"一直都由我来管理
- Of course, Jordan. - And that's the way it is.
历来都是这样子
Everything that's in it and on it is run by me.
这里所有的一切 都是由我拍板
- Jordan, don't raise your voice. - That's the way it's always been too.
别那么大声 一直都是这样的
Everything that has a Reata brand on it is run by me.
所有和"利塔" 有关的事情都由我管理
Does that include me?
也包括我吗?
That's the way my father ran this outfit and the way my grandfather ran it, all of it.
我的父亲和祖父 也都是这样管理的
He kept it together for his son and my father kept it together for his.
他把一切留给了儿子 我父亲也把这一切留给了我
And I'm keeping it together for mine.
我也会把这一切留给我儿子
- All 500,000 square miles? - All of it, for my son.
所有595 000平方公里的土地? 所有这一切 都是我儿子的
You could at least say "our son."
至少你应该说"我们的儿子"
Our son.
我们的儿子
Don't you think that might be just a bit too much for one little baby?
你不觉得这对于 一个小孩来说太多了吗?
Heh. Not if he's a Benedict.
只要是本尼迪特的 孩子就不算多
Well, better hope this is a boy.
你最好希望这是个男孩
Our baby.
我们的孩子
I just said I'm hoping it's a boy.
我只是说我希望是个男孩
What do you mean?
你是什么意思?
I mean, why didn't you tell me?
为何不告诉我?
I'm telling you now.
我现在告诉你了
Well, honey why didn't you tell me?
为何不告诉我?
I mean, well, I should've known.
我该知道的
- You sure? - Sure.
-真的吗? -当然
And our baby is going to be a boy, Jordan. I know it.
我们的孩子会是个男孩  我知道的
A boy very much like his father.
他会非常地像他父亲
In many ways...
在许多方面都像…
...but not all.
但不是全部
Shouldn't she be putting on weight, honey?
她是不是有点轻了?
Well, it's natural, I think, darling, for him to be gaining faster.
我想 他倒是长得有点快了
Let me see.
让我看看
They are heavy.
真沉
Hello, sweetheart.
你好啊 宝贝
Well, he's building up fine.
他长得可真快
"I am now stronger than ever...
"我现在比以前更坚强了"
...and am helping a young Dr. Guerra get started here.
"我在帮助年轻的 吉拉大夫在这里工作"
Most every day I find myself walking three or four miles...
"每天我都要走上 三到四英里的路程"
...to the dusty and dirty street of Vientecito Village.
"来回穿梭与'文特希' 村子的脏乱街道当中"
Hello, Angel. How are you?
安吉尔 你好吗?
I'd like to speak to Mr. Gomez, the boss, the man that runs this place.
我想找戈麦斯先生谈谈 就是管理这地方的人
Mrs. Benedict, what is it I can do?
本尼迪特太太 找我有事吗?
Mr. Gomez, I'm going to leave Dr. Guerra here with you.
戈麦斯先生 我让吉拉大夫住在你这里
He'll tell you a number of things that must be done.
他会告诉你 一些继续着手做的事情的
This place is a scandal.
这地方真的是太脏了
Thank you, Dr. Guerra. I'll get in touch with you.
谢谢你 吉拉大夫 我会和你保持联系的
Hello, Jett.
你好 杰特
- Howdy, Miss Leslie. - How are you?
-你好 莱斯莉小姐 -你好吗?
I'm doing pretty good.
我很好
- You made some improvements. - Do you like it?
-看来你过得还不错 -你喜欢吗?
Looks good.
这里真不错
Well, it ain't much yet, but it's coming right along.
这里虽没那么好 但毕竟有所改善了
- You know, I wouldn't have believed it. - Believed what?
我真不敢相信 相信什么?
Truthfully, I wouldn't have expected this sort of talent to be one of your virtues.
说实在的 我当初 真没想到你本事还挺大的
That's the first time I was ever accused of having any of that.
当初我可是被人 看成是一无是处的
It really is nice, Jett.
这里真的很不错 杰特
Real nice.
真不错
Someday I want to have a place no one will be ashamed of.
有一天… 我这里会让所有人都羡慕
Oh, I cut them out of the newspaper. I thought they'd dress the place up a little bit.
这是我在报纸上剪下来的 我想这或许能让 光秃秃的墙壁好看一点
Sweet of you.
你真可爱
Want to come on in here and sit down?
出来坐在这里歇一会儿好吗?
- Rest a minute? - Thank you.
休息一会儿 -谢谢
Having kids seems to agree with you, you know it?
有了孩子你显得更快乐了
You're looking prettier than ever.
你看起来比以前更漂亮了
Just as good, anyway.
反正就是好
My goodness. And tea.
天啊 是茶!
- You like tea? - Of course, I love it.
你喜欢茶? -当然 我喜欢
Just seems down here everybody drinks gallons of coffee.
是的 这里的人都是喝咖啡的
Yeah, I know it.
我知道
Mind if I pay you a rather personal compliment?
想听我一句奉承的话吗?
What is it?
什么?
You make a very excellent cup of tea.
你泡的茶非常的棒
Yeah, well, I do a lot of things in a pinch.
必要时我可以做很多的事情
Would you like one lump or would you like two?
你想放一块还是两块糖?
Well, I think I'll take mine straight.
我想就这样喝
That's good enough for me.
看来我泡的茶还不错
Oh. Boy. Ahem.
噢 孩子 啊哈
It's not too good, is it?
并没有那么好 对吗?
When are you gonna get married, Jett?
你何时打算结婚呢 杰特?
Don't you need somebody to help you with this kind of responsibility?
你难道不需要人来 帮你打理这个地方吗?
Well, when I get some time to look around, I'll go back East.
当我有时间到处去看看的话 我就会回到东部去…
To Maryland, places...
去马里兰这样的地方
Say, got any good-looking sisters back there might be interested in some poor people?
你还有长得漂亮 又乐意帮助穷人的妹妹吗?
Money isn't all, you know, Jett.
金钱并非一切
Not when you got it. Heh.
你得到它之前就是全部
Jett...
杰特
...the other people around here, why don't they help themselves like you've done?
在这儿附近的其他人… 他们为何不能 像你一样自助呢?
Well, now, ahem, when you say "other people," what do you mean?
你说的"其他人" 指的是谁?
Well, I've just come back from Vientecito.
我刚从"文特希"回来
Oh, that bunch of wetbacks.
就是那些"湿背"住的地方? （非法进入美国的墨西哥人）
Well, don't go getting me mixed up with none of them.
你不能把我和 他们混为一谈
I'm just as much of Texas as Bick Benedict is.
我像毕克一样 都是地道的德州人
- I'm no wetback. - Oh, I know that.
-我可不是"湿背" -我知道
You're like Jordan in that respect, attitude, everything.
在自尊心 态度 很多方面 你都很像乔丹
But your situation is so different. You're a workingman.
但你的处境不一样 你是一个工人
Well, that's something I'm gonna try to fix.
我会做出一番成就的
Someday I will.
终有一天我会的
All right, Gomez.
好的 戈麦斯
Yeah, I understand.
我知道了
Yeah, thank you.
好的 谢谢你
Well, thanks for the tea party, Jett.
谢谢你泡的茶 杰特
And don't be such a stranger.
别老像个陌生人一样
Stop by and pay us a visit.
路过的时候 常来看看我们
Well, I don't know about that.
我也不知道为什么
Old Bick's still got his kettle on for me.
毕克还在为 我的事情耿耿于怀
Leslie?
莱斯莉
Hello, darling.
你好 亲爱的
I was just having tea with Jett Rink.
我刚在杰特那儿喝完茶回来
- Gomez telephoned. - Oh?
戈麦斯打电话来说
"Mrs. Benedict comes to Vientecito. I hope you're not displeased," he said.
"本尼迪特太太到'文特希'去了" 他还说"希望你别生气"
Look, I told you before... What about Jett Rink?
我早就告诉过你… 杰特怎么了?
He made tea. Isn't that unbelievable?
他会泡茶 是不是难以致信?
He does so want to improve himself.
他真的想改善自己的生活
But your man Gomez, that camp he runs...
但那个戈麦斯 他去到那个…
It's hopeless.
真是无可救药
You can't tear around this place with no regard for who you are, interfering with those people.
你要顾及自己的身份 别随便去那个地方 和那些人纠缠在一块
Jordan, that place is a scandal.
乔丹 那个地方很脏
- Dr. Guerra threw his hands up in horror. - That's his problem.
吉拉早就向你求助过的 那是他的问题
You've been a big powerful rich Texan for a hundred years. Do something.
一百年来你们都是有富有德州人 为何不做一些有意义的事情?
I'm not the Red Cross.
我可不是"红十字会" 我只是个养牛人而已
If you won't, I will.
你不去做的话 我去好了
If you go near one of those dumps again, if you get mixed up in this migratory mess, why I'll...
如果你再去那种地方… 如果我再听说你到那些地方去…
Just what will you do?  I'll leave you. That's what I'll do, I'll leave.
-那如何?         -我就休了你!
- Oh, there's my darling little girl. How are you, big boy?
我的宝贝女儿
Did you think your naughty mama was never gonna come up to see you?
你真以为你淘气的妈妈 不会回来看你了吗?
There's one thing you can be sure of.
有一点你必须清楚…
One of these days, I'm gonna run Jett out of this country.
这几天我就劝说 杰特离开这里
Who is it? Can you say hello to Luz?
快跟卢斯问好
Say, "Hello, Luz."
快说"你好 卢斯"
Lookit there. Lookit there. Say hello to little Luz.
快向小卢斯问好
I don't care what you say, Leslie, she does look like Luz.
不管你怎么认为 亲爱的 她真的很像卢斯
Oh, honey.
噢 亲爱的
Y'all are gathered here on this fourth anniversary of my son's birth.
今天 我们来庆祝 我儿子四岁的生日
And your daughter's.
还有你的女儿
Well, of course.
哦 当然
I want to take this auspicious occasion...
我想借此良机跟大家说…
...to say that this young fellow right over here...
大家眼前的这个孩子
...is gonna grow up to be one of Reata's top hands.
将来长大后就会 成为"利塔"的主人
Hi, Daddy.
爸爸
I mean, this boy's gonna be the best.
这孩子会成为最出色的主人
He may even grow up to be better than his old man. Maybe.
或许有朝一日他 会比他的老爸更出色
Oh, girls, look at the pony.
孩子们 看那匹小马
Come on, look at that.
它来了 儿子
There he is, son.
它是你的了
- He's all yours. - All mine, Daddy.
全是我的吗 爸爸?
No!
不
Jordan...
乔丹
Take him around, Angel.
把它牵过来 安吉尔
- Take it easy, son. - Honey, he doesn't want to.
别紧张 儿子 他不想这样
Oh, I rode before I could walk.
我会走路之前就学会了骑马
But that was you. This is another person entirely.
但那是你 他和你不一样
He's a Benedict.
他是本尼迪特家族的子孙
He's gonna stay on that saddle if I have to tie a hitch on him to keep him there.
要让他学会在马背上生活
Take him away.
把它牵走
Angel. No.
安吉尔 不行
Let him ride, Polo.
-不 -让他骑吧 保罗
Let him ride.
让他骑吧
Would you take him up for his nap? I think he's tired.
带他回去睡午觉去 我想他也累了
Ho. There, now, that wasn't so bad, was it, son?
还不错 是吗 儿子?
Leslie...
莱斯莉
...Bick knows all there is to know about running a ranch. Bone, hide and hair.
毕克精通经营牧场的一切 这里的一草一木
He don't know a dang thing about raising kids any more than his father did.
但他不懂得如何抚养孩子 比他父亲好不了多少
So you just stay with it your way.
你要按照自己的方法
Help those children grow up to be what they want to be.
让孩子们长大后做 他们自己想做的事情
I will, Uncle Bawley. I promise.
我会的 保莱叔叔 我保证
Well...
好的
...we're gonna hit the hay.
我们要睡觉去了
- Night, Leslie. Night.
-晚安 莱斯莉 -晚安
- Night, Bick. - Night, Pink.
-晚安 毕克 -晚安 平克
Good night, kids.
晚安 孩子们
Night, Vashti.
晚安 维斯泰
Well, I guess it's time for me to turn in.
我也该上床睡觉了
Night, Bick. Night, Bawley.
- 晚安 毕克 - 晚安 保莱
- Night, Leslie. - Good night, Uncle Bawley.
-晚安 毕克 -晚安 保莱
Good night, everybody. And don't forget to turn off the rain.
晚安 各位 别忘了把窗户关上
Tired?
你累了吗?
No.
没有
Jordan...
乔丹…
What's happening is we're getting on each other's nerves.
我们或许在 一起生活得太久了
Could be.
或许吧
We've been together every day and every night since we first met each other.
自从我们第一次 见面我们就形影不离
Is that bad?
这不好吗?
No.
没有
Only we're getting in the habit of snapping at each other...
我们习惯了 彼此跟对方争论
...on things we should have adjusted to years ago.
这些年来 这些我们都已习惯了
Jordan, I think it would be a good idea...
我想 让孩子们回家
...if I took the children home for a visit.
看一趟或许会比较好
Home?
家?
Well, if you're homesick...
如果你想家的话…
I mean, if that's the way you want it.
我是说  如果你想回去的话
- That's not the way I want it, Jordan. - All right, then.
-这不是为了我 乔丹 -那好吧
It'll be better for us if we're apart for a while.
我们分别一段时间 对彼此都有好处
Better for us and the children.
对我们和孩子都有好处
It'll give us both a chance to think things out for a while.
这也给了我们 一个静静思考的机会
Gee, Les...
诶 莱斯
...I don't know. You know best, I guess.
我想你早就想清楚了
I think it will be best.
我觉得这样最好了
Hi there. Morning.
-你们好         -早上好
Fine day for riding.
今天可是个骑马的好日子
Oh, just magnificent.
简直棒极了
See you later.
一会儿见
She's a lucky girl.
她是个幸运的女孩
If I had it to do it again, I'd still walk off with Jordan.
如果让我重新选择的话 我还是会和乔丹走的
Even if I knew it was gonna end like this.
即使我知道 结果会是这样子
Leslie!
莱斯莉
You'll have no time to be homesick...
没时间想念家了…
...with this wedding and Thanksgiving on us together.
和我们一起共度 这个婚礼和感恩节吧
Here, Pedro. Pedro, come here, Pedro.
"佩德鲁" 快过来
Pedro, Pedro, Pedro.
佩德鲁 佩德鲁 佩德鲁
Pedro, eat your dinner like a good boy.
"佩德鲁" 快过来吃吧
Pedro, eat your dinner like a good boy, Pedro.
佩德鲁 好好吃你的饭
Look at that.
看哪
Merciful Father, we bow our heads in gratitude on this, our Thanksgiving Day.
仁慈的上帝 值此感恩节 我们心怀无限感激
We give thee hearty and humble thanks for thy bounty...
对你的仁慈我们 表以衷心的感激
...beseeching thee to continue thy loving kindness to us...
愿你继续给予 我们这样的仁慈
...that our land may still yield her increase...
让我们的土地丰收
...to thy glory and our comfort. Amen.
让你的仁慈之光普照大地 阿门
Pedro.
佩德鲁
- That Pedro? - That Pedro?
那是"佩德鲁"吗?
Yes, darling. Yes. Mm-hm.
是的 宝贝
Oh, darling.
哦 亲爱的
It's all right, baby.
没事 孩子
No! No!
不
There, now, darling.
哦 亲爱的
Oh, now, darlings.
It's a day when we're supposed to be happy.
今天是我们应该高兴的日子
Come on, now, and smile...
好了 宝贝 笑一笑
...like Mommy.
像妈妈一样
Something wrong, Miss Leslie?
怎么了 莱斯莉小姐?
Now maybe you'll stop crying.
你们都该停止哭泣了
It's a message to you from your father.
这信是你爸爸写来的
Is he gonna be here for dinner?
他要来这儿吃晚餐吗?
Well, no.
不…
But he says:
但他说
"I hope my darlings are all very happy.
"希望我的宝贝们能玩得开心"
I want them to know I miss them very much...
"我想让他们知道 我非常地想念他们
...and love each one very much."
非常地爱他们"
I could see you coming.
我看见你走过来了
Why, Mr. Benedict, this is a good surprise.
本尼迪特先生 这真是莫大的惊喜!
Hello, Jefferson.
你好 杰斐逊
We're having a wedding. Just plenty of excitement.
我们这里正在举行婚礼 大伙儿都高兴极了
Dearly beloved...
"各位相爱的人"
...we are gathered together here in the sight of God and in the face of this company...
"今天 我们在这里 谨代表上帝见证这一对新人"
...to join together this man and this woman in holy matrimony...
"见证这位男士和 这位女士的神圣结合"
...which is an honorable estate instituted of God.
"这也是上帝的荣耀和恩典"
David, wilt thou have this woman to thy wedded wife?
戴维 你愿意娶这位女士为妻吗?
To live together after God's ordinance in the holiest state of matrimony?
"在这神圣时刻 谨尊上帝的旨意而永远相随"
Wilt thou love her, comfort her, honor...
"你能终身爱她 尊敬她…"
...and keep her in sickness and in health...
"无论是健康或者疾病
...and forsaking all others...
都能放弃所有的一切…"
...keep thee only unto her so long as ye both shall live?
"在你们的有生之年 彼此常相厮守吗?"
I will.
我愿意
Lacey, wilt thou have this man to thy wedded husband...
"蕾茜 你愿意嫁给 这位男士作为你的丈夫"
...to live together after God's ordinance in the holiest state of matrimony?
"在这神圣时刻 谨尊上帝的旨意而永远相随"
Wilt thou love him, comfort him, honor and keep him...
"你能终身爱她 尊敬他…"
...in sickness and in health, and forsaking all others...
"无论是健康或者疾病 都能放弃所有的一切…"
...keep thee only unto him so long as ye both shall live?
"在你们的有生之年 彼此常相厮守吗?"
I will.
我愿意
Bless, O Lord, this ring...
"祝福他们吧 上帝 这个戒指…"
...that he who gives it and she who wears it may abide in thy peace...
"他给她带上的那一刻 就意味着他们永恒的结合"
...and continue in thy favor unto their life's end.
"彼此相爱 直到生命的终点"
Amen.
"阿门"
With this ring, I thee wed.
戴上这个戒指 你们就正式结婚了
Those whom God hath joined together...
"上帝祝福你们
...let no man put asunder.
永远都不分开"
For as much as David and Lacey...
"戴维和蕾茜彼此同意
...have consented together in holy wedlock...
这一神圣的结合"
...I pronounce that they are man and wife.
我宣布 你们正式成为夫妻
Are you ready to come back to your old beat-up cowhand?
你准备回到 这个老牧牛工身边吗?
Jordan, I'm no different than I was when I left.
我和我离开时丝毫没变
Well, we Texans like a little vinegar in our greens, honey. Gives them flavor.
我们德州人的活力 让大草原别有一番风味
What do you think of old King Tut? - Boy, howdy. Some hunk of beef.
你们觉得这头 "老牛王"怎么样? 伙计们 它身上的肉可真够多的!
He's gonna make history too.
它也会成为历史的
By the time Bick finishes his breeding program, he'll have an animal...
当毕克完成他的饲养计划 他就会养出一头…
...that's 99% beef and the rest exaggeration.
全身百分之九十九 都是肉的牛来
Say, Ollie...
欧利
...see that?
你看见了吗?
That's Rink's truck. I don't want him hauling through my place anymore.
那是林克的卡车 我不想让他在我的地方乱转
Jett's got the easement, Bick.
杰特可以在 别人的土地上开车
He's got a right to go through the land. No two ways about that.
他有这个权利 这无可争议
I'm sick and tired of his prospecting. I want him out.
我讨厌他在这里探矿 我想他立即离开这里
He's borrowed about all he could. He's down to his last collar button, Bick.
他借来了所以能借来的东西 他现在真是穷得丁当响了
Sure is.
是的
Buy him out, Ollie. Buy him out, and get him out of here.
给他开个价 欧利 然后让他赶紧滚蛋
Hello, Jett.
你好啊 杰特
What do you want?
你来干嘛?
My well came in, Bick.
我的油井出油了 毕克
Fine.
好啊
Why, that's wonderful, Jett.
太好了 杰特
Everybody thought I had a duster.
大伙儿都以为我 那口井不会出油
You all thought Spindletop and Burk Burnett was all the oil there was.
你们都以为只有 "史宾雷特"和"贝克伯纳"有油井
Well, I'm here to tell you it ain't.
我是来告诉你们 其实不是的 这里也有油井
It's here. And there ain't a dang thing you gonna do about it.
还有一件让 你们羡慕的事情
My well came in big, so big.
我的油井很大
And there's more down there, and there's bigger wells.
这地下还有 更多更大的油井
I'm rich, Bick!
我有钱了 毕克!
I'm a rich one.
我是个有钱人了
I'm a rich boy.
I'll have more money than you ever thought you could have.
我会比你有更多 你无法想象得到的钱
You and all the rest of you stinking sons of Benedicts.
比你和本尼迪特的 子孙都要有钱
Leslie, you go in the house. Take the women with you.
莱斯莉 带上其他女士回到房间里去
Jett, we're real glad you struck it.
杰特 我们很高兴你挖出石油了
Now, you go on along home.
现在 你赶紧回家去吧
Oh, my, you sure do look pretty, Miss Leslie.
你真的很漂亮 莱斯莉小姐
You always did look pretty.
你一直都很漂亮
Just good enough to eat.
漂亮得… 让人想咬上一口
Wait a minute, Bick. Wait a minute.
等等
Boy, take it easy, take it easy.
冷静点!
Wait a minute.
等一下
My, you're testy, Bick.
你太暴躁了 毕克
You're testy as an old cook.
暴躁得像一个老厨子一样
Bick...
毕克
...you should have shot him a long time ago. Now he's too rich to kill.
你早就该一枪把他崩了 现在他有钱 谁也动不了他了
You tell your client that Reata's my property...
跟你客户说"利塔"是我的财产
...and the name of Reata's my property.
"利塔"这个名字也是我的财产
Texas courts are fair.
德州法庭会是公平的
He's to cease using the name of my ranch in his oil schemes.
用我牧场的名字来开油井 他一定会受惩罚
I won't have oil-digging on Reata, and I won't stand for its name being used.
在"利塔"农场我是不会钻油井的 我也不能忍受"利塔" 这个名字被乱用
Is that clear?
明白了吗?
Ma?
妈妈?
Mother!
They say Aunt Luz was in love with Jett Rink...
有人说卢斯阿姨 真的爱上杰特.林克了
...even if she was old enough to be his mother.
虽然她都老得 可以做人家妈妈
Now, Luz.
卢斯…
She was a character.
They say she was always trying to keep him from getting married.
她总是想阻止他结婚
He had to run off to marry you.
要娶你 他只能逃走了
What's that?
什么?
Who said what?
谁说的?
Oh, somebody. I forget.
某人吧 我不记得是谁了
Heh. You know what they say?
知道他们是怎么说的吗?
They say that every girl in Texas was trying to catch Papa.
他们说 德州所有女孩 都想把爸爸钓上
They said, quote, that "there wasn't a prize bull like him...
他们说…我引用一句: "自从山姆.休斯顿成婚以后
...since Sam Houston got married."
就再没这么有魅力的男人了"
That's enough from her, Leslie.
她该闭嘴了
I'm sure it's quite true, darling.
亲爱的 这在我听起来完全真实
It took me two whole days to land him.
我花了两整天时间才钓上他呢
Oh, really? It all sounds so fascinating and uncouth.
是吗?
Where are you going?
你去哪?
Down the road to Smitty's for a Coke.
到楼下路口斯米梯 商店买可乐
With who? - Nobody.
跟谁去? 不跟谁
Stay home.
给我呆在家
Hey, you.
嘿 你!
Hello, Papa.
你好 爸爸
Howdy.
你好
- Where you been? - Down the road for a Coke.
你去哪儿了? 到楼下路口 那买可乐去了
With who? - Bob.
跟谁去的? 鲍勃
- Howdy, Mr. Benedict. Hello, Bob.
-你好 本尼迪特先生 -你好 鲍勃
Well, good night, Mr. Benedict.
嗯 晚安了 本尼迪特先生
Excuse me, Papa.
爸爸
Look, Papa, you busy now, Papa?
你现在忙吗?
Never too busy for you, young fella.
年轻人 你有事 我怎么忙都会理你
What's on your mind?
在想什么呢?
Well, Daddy, it's like this.
爸爸 是这样的
I am, Mama. I'm gonna be.
我…妈妈 我要…
I want to go to Harvard and then on to Columbia premed.
我要先去哈佛上学 然后去读哥伦比亚医学院预科
So you want to be a doctor?
这么说来你想做医生?
Yes, ma'am.
是
What about Reata, Jordy?
小乔丹 那"利塔"牧场怎么办呢?
He's counting on you to take over.
他可是指望你去接管"利塔"的
Yeah, I know he is. I know it.
我知道 我知道
But there's 50,000 guys can do it better than I can.
但这世上最起码有五万人 能比我在这一行做得更好
I don't want to live my life pushing cows around.
我不想以后一生 就在"利塔"牧场牧牛
Oh, Mama, I'd die for Papa if I had to.
如果为爸爸而死 我不会犹豫
Your father doesn't want you to die for him. He wants you to live for him.
你爸爸并不想你为他而死 他要你为他活下去
Talk to her, will you, Daddy?
爸爸 你跟她说 好吗?
Reason with her.
跟她讲道理
- I don't want this pinned on me. - I'll take all the blame.
我可不想她怪罪于我 如果妈妈要怪责 我会承担一切
You just sort of soften the blow a little bit.
你只要帮我先把 妈妈的气降低一点就好
I'll talk to him myself.
我自己跟他说吧
You can sway him, Mama. I know you can.
妈妈 我相信你能劝服他的 你能
It's not gonna be easy, honey.
宝贝 这个可不是件容易的事
Well, maybe I can catch her at a weak moment.
也许我可以在 她松懈的时候劝服她
You can do it, Daddy. I know you can.
爸爸 我知道你能办到的 你能的
Darling, I've been thinking...
亲爱的 我在想些事儿…
Me too.
我也正在想着些事儿…
About the children.
是关于孩子们的
That's funny. Me too.
真巧 我也是
We must be getting old.
我们看来定必是老了
Speak for yourself.
你说说看你在想什么?
I wonder if we'd love them enough to do what's really right for them.
我疑惑 按我们的法则为他们做些 正确的安排是否算真正爱他们
Why, sure.
为什么这么想?这是当然的啊
I hope so.
我也希望如此
I mean so we love them too much, perhaps.
我是说… 也许我们爱他们实在太深了
So much we keep from doing what's right for them.
深得我们为他们做了 太多对他们好的事情
Not me.
我可没有
You don't have to worry about me.
你不用担心我
It's always the mother.
问题总是出在母亲一方
Theory is, she don't want her fledglings...
有个理论非常有理 因为母亲总不希望雏鸟
...to leave her nest and try their own wings.
离开自己的巢穴 让它们振翅高飞
All that sort of stuff.
就是这么回事
You mean...
你是说…
...you'd be perfectly willing to sacrifice?
你会愿意牺牲自己的利益 让孩子们振翅高飞?
Yeah.
当然
I'd sacrifice for her. You know that.
我愿意为她牺牲 你知道的
I'm not so sold...
我不是很赞同你
...on that girls' school in Switzerland you're stuck on.
坚持让她念的那间… 瑞士的女子学校
Now, don't get your feathers up.
别立马就开始发飙
Judy's not so crazy about that Switzerland stuff either.
茱迪自己也对 那学校没什么兴趣
Of course she isn't. That's exactly why she needs to go.
她当然没兴趣 但正是因为这样她才必须去
Well, I wouldn't push her.
我不会逼她的
She, uh...
她…
...wants to go to Texas Tech.
想上德州工学院
- That is a man's school. - Well, girls go too.
那是男子学校 但也有女生在那上学
It's got the best animal-husbandry course in the country, she says.
她说那里有 全国最好的畜牧专业
She wants to be a rancher like her old man.
她想像他爸爸一样当个农场主
Like Bob Dace.
像鲍勃一样吧
She's just got a little schoolgirl crush on that hulking Bob Dace.
她只是为那丑陋不堪的 鲍勃着迷而已
Well, she's got her mind set on it.
反正她的心意 已经打死那上面了
That's what she wants.
那才是她想要的
And I, for one, am willing to sacrifice.
而我 就是打算为她牺牲的一个
Well...
好吧
What do you say?
你怎么说?
It seems we've hatched an odd pair of fledglings, darling.
看来我们孵养的雏鸟 还真是够特立独行的
Yeah.
Brace yourself.
你听清楚了
Jordy wants to be a doctor.
小乔丹想做医生
- He wants what? - He wants to be a doctor. He's set on it.
他想做什么? 他想做医生 他绝对是打死主意在这上面
Over my dead body.
除非我死了吧
- You know what he's supposed to do. - Well, he's not.
你应该清楚他应该做什么的 但他不干
He'd die for you, but he's not going to live his life for you. And he's right.
他愿意为你而死 但是他不应该为你过 自己不愿意过的生活
He'll do as we've all done.
他必须按照我们为 他订下的路子走下去
He wants to go to Harvard first and then to Columbia premed.
他想先上哈佛 然后读哥伦比亚医学院预科
You're pretty handy with those terms.
你对那些术语说得 还是挺琅琅上口的吗
I can see who's been cooking this thing up.
我知道是谁在幕后搞鬼了
Of course...
当然了…
...this would mean a big sacrifice on your part.
这对你来说算是大牺牲了吧
Well...
好吧
...no matter where he goes to school...
我不管他去哪里上学…
...he comes right back home and runs Reata.
反正他以后都要给 我回家接掌"利塔"
Well, I guess you were right about one thing, Jordan.
我看你有一件事是对的
Me?
我?
On one thing.
在一件事上
We are getting old.
我们越来越老了
Who? - We are, Jordan.
谁? 我们 乔丹
We're the older generation.
我们是老一辈了
Aren't we?
不是吗?
Suddenly.
突然地
Yeah.
是的
I guess so.
可能是吧
"... until a well 1000 feet in depth has been drilled...
"…除非石油或天然气
...unless oil or gas shall have been struck at a lesser depth."
不用挖那么深就可以产出"
Is that Vashti Hake's ranch?
那是用于 维斯泰.海克的牧场的条约?
- Yes. - Heh.
是的
Good.
很好
- How about Reata? - No.
那"利塔"的呢? 没有
That Benedict's a hard guy to crack.
本尼迪特是个顽固派
Let's just keep punching, boys.
那就继续努力
Hey, you.
嘿 你
Hospital. What's he covering up now?
[杰特.林克向医院捐献]医院! 他到底掩盖些什么呢?
That hombre's going to overstep the mark one of these days.
他可成为了 最近的风云人物
Just give him enough rope.
给他足够长的绳索
- Give him enough rope and he'll hang you. - Heh.
给他的绳索够长 你就被他勒死了
I'll get it.
我来听
Hello?
喂
Yes?
No, this is her daughter.
不 我是他女儿
You did?
是吗?
Oh, you have to find that out for yourself.
你得自己找出来
Luz, take your social life on the other phone.
-要进行社交去用另一部电话 -是你的电话
It's for you. I think he's nice.
他好像挺好的
- Who's nice? Jett Rink.
-谁?         -杰特.林克
- I don't want to talk to him. - What will I tell him?
我不想和他通话 我怎么跟他说?
Let me talk.
我来说吧 我来跟他说
I'll tell him.
我会跟他说
I'll talk to him.
还是我跟他通话吧
Hello?
喂?
You've heard from me before on this, Jett.
杰特 没打这通电话之前 你已经收到我的消息了吧
Judge Whiteside told you, and I told you.
看来是怀特赛德跟你说的 现在我告诉你
This is a cattle ranch, not an oil field. That's the way it's gonna stay.
这是个牧场 不是油田 所以以后它还是牧场
About the most expensive call you ever made.
毕克 这看来是你接过的 最为"昂贵"的一通电话了
Cost you a billion dollars a year for the next 50 years.
接下来50年 这会让 你每年付出10亿美元的代价
Couldn't we have just one little itty-bitty oil well so I could get my own private phone?
我们能不能开一口小小的油井 然后我就能装一部私人电话了
The Naval Secretary told a press conference...
报告罗斯福总统后 海军大臣告知媒体…
...that the battleship Arizona and five other warships were lost...
亚历桑那号战舰和另外五艘战
...in the Japanese air raid on the naval base at Pearl Harbor...
在两星期前日本对 珍珠港空袭之中被击毁
...a fortnight ago.
他报告说有目前已知…
He reported that 91 officers...
共有91名军官以及
...and 2638 enlisted men were known dead.
2638名现役军人死亡
Aside from the Arizona...
除亚利桑那外
That only makes me realize that I'm losing you.
这只会让我觉得我在失去你
Round yon virgin mother and child
#圣光环绕圣母圣婴#
Holy infant so tender and mild
#圣洁婴孩纯真可爱#
Sleep in heavenly peace
#尽享天赐安眠#
Jingle bells, jingle bells Jingle all the way
#叮叮当 叮叮当 铃儿响叮当#
Oh, what fun it is to ride In a one-horse open sleigh, hey
#今晚滑雪多快乐 我们坐在雪橇上#
Jingle bells, jingle bells
#叮叮当 叮叮当 铃儿响叮当#
- Here they are. - Hello.
他们来了 -你好
- Come on down. When did you two sneak in?
过来 你们两个什么时候溜进来的?
The honeymooners.
甜蜜小俩口
Running off and getting married like that.
茱迪 很快就会有蜜月可度了
Boy, you're gonna get it. You know Mom wanted a big wedding.
你知道你妈一向希望 你能有一个盛大婚礼
Now, that's not true, Luz.
卢斯 不是这样的
Oh, darling.
哦 亲爱的
Well, not quite true.
不是完全这样
Come down here and face the jury.
过来对着陪审团
Come on down, darling.
过来 亲爱的
Howdy. Merry Christmas.
早上好 圣诞快乐
See what your mama and papa brought you from Dallas.
看看爸爸妈妈给你从达拉斯带来了什么
Oh, lucky you! Isn't that beautiful?
哦 你真幸运 这很漂亮 对吧?
Oh, Judy. Look at that.
茱迪 看那儿
Thank you, Mother.
谢谢你 妈妈
Well.
好
We came for you to see Angel.
我们来是让 大家见见安吉尔的
He's the first soldier from Reata.
他是"利塔" 农场出的第一名战士
- Merry Christmas, Polo. Merry Christmas.
-保罗 圣诞快乐 -圣诞快乐
My. Isn't he a fine-looking soldier?
看这小战士多么英俊?
Oh, just a minute.
稍等一下
Merry Christmas, Angel.
安吉尔 圣诞快乐
Thank you.
谢谢
Today the wish of all of us is that the war ends quickly...
今天我们共同的祝愿 是这场战争早日结束…
...and that you, Angel, return safely to Reata...
而你 安吉尔 能安全回到"利塔"来…
...and to all of those who love you very much.
敬所有深爱你的人
I'll drink a toast to that with anything in force.
我们干杯
Come on now, and open it.
来 快 打开看看
- Hello, Dr. Guerra. - Hello, Dr. Benedict.
-你好 吉埃拉医生 -你好 本尼迪特医生
Just a little premature.
我还只是见习而已
Oh, I know, it takes time.
我知道这需要时间
- Oh, Jordan, this is Juana. - Hello.
乔丹 这位是胡安娜
She's been training out at the hospital.
正在医院受培训
Must be that darn north wind static or something. Ha, ha.
一定是因为吹北风了 这才产生的静电
Don't tell me that you haven't learned that dry wind, friction and a heavy carpet...
你没听说过干燥 摩擦 还有厚重的地毯…
...are not the only means of creating electricity between human beings.
并不只是两人之间 产生静电的唯一几种方式?
How are you? Oh, Dr. Guerra.
你好啊 噢  吉埃拉医生
- Thank you.
谢谢
Hey, Angel?
嗨 安吉尔
Can't you hang around and give me the lowdown on what it's like?
能不能留下跟我 说说军中的一些情况?
- See y'all. - See you later, Pinky.
再见 -再见
Juana?
胡安娜
- Oh. Very nice meeting you. - Nice meeting you.
-很高兴见到你 -我也很高兴见到你
- Goodbye, Adios.
-再见 -再见
- Boys, let's get us some Christmas cheer. - You talked me into it.
-我们来为圣诞干几杯吧 -你说服我了
I'll go for that.
我要喝几杯
I was afraid we were going to have a mighty dry Christmas.
朋友们 看来我们今年的 圣诞会过得非常不错哦
I'm going to drink a toast to the two young men of Reata.
我现在要敬在 "利塔"的两个年轻人
My two sons.
我两个孩子
Jordy...
茱迪
...and Robert.
和罗伯特
Thank you, Mr. Benedict.
谢谢 本尼迪特先生
Better take it easy on the bourbon, Dad.
少喝点威士忌吧 爸爸
It's not good for you.
对你身体不好的
I'm not kidding you.
我不是和你开玩笑的
Certainly hate to see Angel go.
我不想见到安吉尔离开
That boy is the best dang man on the place.
那孩子是我们 这片地方最出色的男人
Now that you've finished college, it's time for you to take your place here...
现在是到你接管这里 为我们的战争
...and produce beef for the war.
提供出粮食的时候
They need doctors, Dad. They need doctors in war too.
他们也需要医生啊 爸爸 战争也需要医生
I'm going to finish medical school if I can.
如果可以 我希望能完成医学院的学习
You are being bullheaded.
你真是顽固得紧
I never would be any good running this place.
这片地方归我管我 永远也做不好的
Any man on Reata can do it better.
"利塔"中的任何人 都能比我做得好
Jordy, you're the one...
你是唯一的一人
...with a responsibility to Reata.
你是对"利塔"负 有责任的唯一一人
Your blood pressure's going up just while we're talking here.
我们在这里交谈时 你的血压就升高了
Now, please, Papa, it isn't good for you. Just relax.
拜托 这对你没好处的 放松点好不好
Don't you get fresh with me.
别以为我什么都不懂
We're talking.
我们在交谈呢
Yes, I heard.
我有听到
It's Christmas morning.
现在可是圣诞节的凌晨
Isn't this something that could be discussed tomorrow?
你们明天再讨论这些事情不行吗?
There's nothing to discuss.
没有什么好讨论的
When I come home, I'm gonna work with Dr. Guerra in Vientecito.
我回家后就会去"文塞塔" 医院跟吉埃拉医生一起工作
I love Texas as much as you do, Dad, and I want to work here.
我对德州的爱不少于你 我想在此地工作
I just want to work in a different way, that's all.
只不过我希望做的 是不同的工作罢了
Come on, Jordy.
别这样 乔丹
Work with Guerra.
跟吉埃拉一起工作
Here's to you, Mr. Benedict.
这杯是敬你的 本尼迪特先生
You look beat, Mr. Benedict.
你看来好像不行了哦 本尼迪特先生
Here's to you. It's pretty good stuff.
敬你 这些酒非常棒
You make that yourself?
自己弄的吗?
Make it every year.
是啊 我每年都弄的
My Christmas special.
我过圣诞节的特制品
No, sir, I mean the liquor.
我是说这些酒
Do you make the liquor yourself?
这些酒是你自己弄的吗?
If you don't, it's about the only thing you don't produce on Reata yourself.
但如果不是的话 恐怕这是"利塔"牧场里面 你唯一不自己弄的东西了
Say, boy.
过来坐下
Come over here and sit down. I got some serious talk to make with you.
我有些话想要认真和你谈谈
I've been watching you pretty close for a lot of years.
我跟你近距离接触 也有很多年了
You're a ranchman.
你是名放牧人
And you're smart.
而且你很聪明
You're wondering why I'm talking to you.
你一定奇怪我 为什么要跟你谈
Bob Dace...
鲍勃…
...look me right in the eye.
看着我的眼睛
You could never be anything but a rancher. Could you?
除了放牧人 你还能成为其他别人吗?
- No, sir. - That's my boy.
-不能 先生 -这才是我的乖孩子
But somebody else thinks I could.
但有别的人认为我可以
Not Judy. Not my Judy.
不是茱迪?
- No, sir, it's not Judy. - Who?
-不是 先生 不是茱迪 -谁?
President Roosevelt.
罗斯福总统
Listen to this.
听听这个:
"To Robert Haskell Dace:
"致罗伯特.哈斯科尔.戴斯"
Greetings from the president of the United States."
"来自美国总统的问候"
Let me see that.
让我看看
"You are hereby notified to report...
"接此信后请于 12月28日前来报道"
...on December 28th, 5 a.m., for induction."
"凌晨五点进行 宣誓入伍仪式"
Well, it don't matter.
没关系
Your draft board won't let you leave this place.
你的工作不会容许 你离开这片地方的
They'll make you stay. This is just as important as carrying a gun.
你的工作会让你一直呆在这里 这工作跟提枪上战场一样重要
I appreciate your confidence, sir, but...
非常感激您的厚爱 先生
Well, this is one thing that I'm not gonna try to get out of.
但这一回我不打算放弃
Fine. Heh.
好吧
Have it your way. You might as well.
随你便 你跟其他人…
Everybody else does around here.
做的事情没什么两样
Well, I'll show you my heart's in the right place.
我会让你看到 我的心摆的位置正确着呢
When you come back and this fracas is over with...
等战后你回来… 管理这牧场的工作
...the job's yours.
就归你管了
It'll be waiting for you.
我会等着你
I couldn't take it, sir.
我不能接受 先生
Papa, Bob and I have planned.
爸爸 鲍勃和我已有计划
We want a place just our own.
我们需要一个二人的天地
You crazy kids, you.
你们这些小鬼 神经病了!
Can you imagine you'll ever have anything like this?
你们有想象过自己能 拥有像"利塔"这样的财富吗?
- Like Reata? - Gosh, no, sir. We just want a little place.
天哪 当然没有 先生 我们只想要一小片天地就好
Just a little place, Daddy, that will allow us time for experimentation and progress.
小小的天地 可以给我们时间 去进行试验 去进步
You see, sir, well, big stuff is old stuff now.
先生 你那些大事对我们来说 只不过是一些老人家的情感
"Big stuff is old stuff"?
大事不过是老人家的情感?
Daddy, Bob didn't mean to upset you.
鲍勃不是想顶你的 爸爸
He just wants to be honest, that's all.
他只是实话实说而已
We just want something little that's our own, that's all.
我们只想要一个属于 我们自己的小天地 这就够了
Just ours. You see, Dad?
只是属于我们的小天地 你明白吗 爸爸?
Yeah, honey. I see.
我懂了 宝贝
See you, Daddy.
再见 爸爸
Hey, Angel, come on.
嗨 安吉儿 听着
Keeping it together all my life for them.
我为这片土地花了 自己一辈子时间
I battled in mesquite, dust, wind...
和灌木 尘土 风沙作斗争…
...keeping it big.
使得这片牧场如此繁荣壮大
And for who?
但为谁呢?
I might just as well give it back to the dirt-eating Comanches.
最后还不是要 还给本地那些肮脏的土著
That's the Christmas spirit. Give it all back to the poor old Indians.
这就是这个 圣诞的精义所在了 爸爸 把这片土地还给 贫苦的印第安人吧
Don't tell me, I know.
不用跟我说 我知道
You're Jett Rink.
你是杰特.林克
- You're Judy? No, I'm Luz.
你是茱迪 不是 我是卢斯
Oh. Luz Benedict.
哦 卢斯 本尼迪特
Ha, ha. That I am. Come on in.
是我 进来
Dad's over at the bar.
爸爸在吧台那边
Feel free, it's Christmas. Everybody gets one.
放松点 今天是圣诞 人人都有礼物的
Christmas?
圣诞?
I thought that was next week.
我还以为下星期才是呢
- Somebody ought to have told me about that. - Ha, ha.
其他人应该早点告诉我的
Christmas greetings from Mr. Jetexas himself.
杰特给自己的圣诞祝福
Hello, Bick.
你好 毕克
Sit down.
请坐吧
I guess Christmas is just about as good a day as any to talk a little business.
我看圣诞节也跟其他 谈生意的时候没什么两样
Run along, Luz.
你先下去 卢斯
We got business to talk about.
我们有话要谈
Bye, now.
先走了
Bye, Mr. Rink.
再见 林克先生
Everybody calls me Jett, honey.
小姐 人人都称呼我杰特的
Bye-bye.
再见
What's on your mind?
你在想什么?
The country needs petroleum.
国家需要石油
I'm going to Washington, Bick.
毕克 我准备要去华盛顿
The reason I'm going, and the reason I'm here, is oil.
我要去那的原因和我 来这的原因都是因为石油
I figured.
我看得出来
Want to talk a little business?
想谈谈生意吗?
I'm ready.
随时恭候
Seems like every time we made a deal, me and you...
似乎每次我们做生意的时候 我和你之间的…
...it just turned out pretty lucky...
结果总是非常幸运…
...for somebody.
对某些人而言
You know, all this oil around here hasn't made a lot of difference.
这附近的石油 也没造成什么不同
We live pretty much the way we always have here at Reata.
我们现在住的跟以前我们 住在"利塔"时候也差不多一样
- Mm-hm. Just like we Benedicts found it. - Yeah.
就跟我们本尼迪特家族 开创这里时一样
Bick...
毕克
...Lord was good to you, setting that concrete pool right down in your own yard.
上帝待你真是不赖 直接就在你前院给你 安排了个游泳池
Hey, come on in. Ha, ha.
下来啊
Oh, not now, Luz.
现在不行 卢斯
Well, it's good for the young folks.
对年轻人来说是好事
We'd have made improvements around here, oil or no oil.
不管有石油没石油 我们在这里已经取得了进步
Now, Bick, that 27.5 percent tax exemption on oil helped out some, didn't it?
但对石油进行27.5%税收豁免 的确是有帮助的 对不对?
- Bale, I'll tell you what old Pinky thinks. - What?
贝利 我来告诉你 一些老人的愚见吧 愿闻其详?
That oil tax exemption is the best thing to hit Texas since we whupped Geronimo.
自从烟草之后 石油税收豁免 是对德州冲击最大的事物了
Yahoo!
呦吼!
One of the finest laws ever passed in Washington.
这是华盛顿 通过的最好的法案之一
All joking aside, Bick...
毕克 我不是开玩笑…
...Bale and I are not adverse to accepting a share of the credit for it.
这些事情我们有泰半功劳 这点我们不该拒绝接受
Not at all.
一点也不
How about an exemption for depreciation of first-class brains, senator?
参议员 有些以往的一流人物 如今逐渐老了 你何不也给 他们进行一番税收豁免?
Whose? Yours?
谁?你?
My father's, for instance.
比如说我父亲
He spent his life saving other people's lives.
他花了一生时间去拯救世人性命
How about some tax exemption there?
何不给他进行点税收豁免
Leslie's always been real sharp-talking, hasn't she, Bick?
莱斯利说话一向一针见血 对吧?
Fair enough, judge. You've always been smooth enough for two.
非常正确 但你也一向能言善辩
Do you take each other for better or for worse...
"无论前路是好 是坏…"
...for richer or for poorer...
"无论是贫 是富…"
...in sickness and in health, until death?
"无论是疾 是康 你们愿意执子之手 直到老逝吗?"
Jordan Benedict...
"乔丹.本尼迪特
...wilt thou take Juana Villalobos, here present...
你愿意接受…" "你身旁的胡安娜.韦拉波斯…"
...for your lawful wife...
"在教堂经历圣母之仪式
...according to the rite of our holy mother, the Church?
让她成为你合法的妻子吗?"
I will.
我愿意
Juana Villalobos...
"胡安娜.韦拉波斯
...wilt thou take Jordan Benedict, here present...
你愿意接受…" "你身旁的乔丹.本尼迪特…"
...for your lawful husband...
"在教堂经历圣母之仪式
...according to the rite of our holy mother, the Church?
让他成为你合法的丈夫吗?"
I will.
我愿意
Join your hands and kneel down.
两手紧握 双膝下跪
Turn right back and then go along
The lady in the front and the gent follow along
Now you're home and now you swing Round and round with a pretty little thing
On the corner with the old left hand It's a right to your honey and a right, now round
Hurry up, Grandpa, can't you see You ain't as spry as you used to be
Barbed-wire gates and a great big date Promenade round or you're gonna get sprayed
Now the gals to the center and back to the bar And the gents to the center with a right-hand star
Now back to the left and not too far
Greet your honey, pass her by Pick up the next gal on the sly
Now the gals go in with a full turn round Like a jaybird walking on the frozen ground
Now the men go in with a full turn round Like a scared little rabbit chased by a hound
Spread that star way out wide Let's do-si-do on every side
Do-si-high and do-si-low Just turn around and here we go
Gals to the center and back to the bar The gents to the center with a right-hand star
Now back to the left and not too far
Greet your honey, pass her by Pick up the next gal on the sly
Now the gals go in with a full turn round Like a jaybird walking on the frozen ground
Yahoo!
#呦哈#
Now the men go in with a full turn round Like a scared little rabbit chased by a hound
Spread that star way out wide Let's do-si-do on every side
What did they say?
他们说什么?
Gals to the center and back to the bar And the gents...
Friends and neighbors, uh...
朋友们 亲邻们…
...I want you all to meet my wife.
我给大家介绍一下我的妻子
- This is Mrs. Jordan Benedict III. Well, congratulations.
乔丹.本尼迪特三世太太
Congratulations.
恭喜!
He was the first Reata baby I ever saw.
"安吉尔今日灵柩归故土"
I remember it as if it were yesterday when I picked him up.
他是我第一个 见到在"利塔"诞生的孩子 那就仿如昨天的事历历在目
He had a fever.
他当时发了烧
I didn't think he was going to live the day out.
我还以为他活不过那天了
On behalf of the United States Army...
我仅代表美国军队
...I am proud to present to you the flag of our nation...
给您自豪地献上 我们国家的旗帜…
...which your son defended so gallantly.
您儿子在战役中非常光荣 地所要拼力保护的旗帜
Oh, say, can you see
By the dawn's early light
What so proudly we hailed
At the twilight's last gleaming?
Whose broad stripes and bright stars
Through the perilous fight
O'er the ramparts we watched
Were so gallantly streaming?
And the rocket's red glare
The bombs bursting in air
Gave proof through the night
That our flag was still there
Oh, say does that star-spangled...
Everyone, just everyone in the world's gonna be there.
全世界所有人都会去那里的
I'm gonna fly up to Dallas and I'm going to Neiman's.
我要飞去达拉斯 到妮梦玛珂丝（著名服装店）去
I'm gonna buy myself a sort of a starlight-white evening dress.
给自己买件光芒闪耀的夜礼服
Very plain and simple, and deadly.
简单明了 但又漂亮不凡
Before you get so elaborately simple, you'd better hear what your father has to say.
在你作好 这些计划之前… 你该先听听你父亲的意见
We're certainly going. I promised Jett.
我们怎样都要去的 我答应杰特了
Jett. What are you talking about?
杰特?你在说什么?
He likes me. He likes my family too.
他喜欢我 也喜欢我的家人
He's always talking about you.
他一直谈起你唉
My dear, darling Luz.
亲爱的卢斯…
If I didn't know you had a Benedict head on those immature shoulders...
如果你不是还在 没发育成熟的肩上 顶着颗本尼迪特家的头
...I'd prescribe a good spanking.
我早把你狠狠揍一顿了
Oh, he's dreamy.
他好迷人
Ask the Snythe girls. Ask anyone.
你可以问问那些女孩 问所有人
He's just a rough diamond.
他是一块待雕琢的玉
He's a rough rhinestone, and he's old enough to be your father.
是人造的玉而已 他老得都够当你父亲了
- What are you six evil men up to now? - Oh, honey.
你们这六个怪老头在这干吗呢? 宝贝
It's a coronation. Old Jett's fixing to get himself crowned king.
我们这是在举行加冕礼 杰特打算加冕成王了
Gotta have 10 million to be on the list.
最起码要有1000万美元 才可能出现在宾客名单里面
All the most important people in the country will be there.
整个国家的重要人物都会出席
A coast-to-coast broadcast. Jett's gonna make a magnificent speech.
还会有现场直播 杰特要进行词藻华丽的演说
I know. Ha, ha. I'm gonna write it for him.
我知道 我正准备为他写这演说稿呢
It'll be heard across the nation by everyone.
全国上下都会听到的
Eliminating one. - Yeah?
把一个人排除掉吧
- That's me. - Good.
就是我
Hooray!
万岁
You stay away, you'll be the only folks in Texas who ain't there.
你们不参加的话看来 全加州也就你们没去了
I suppose you're right. - You're roped in with the herd.
你们得合群点
You'll be dancing to Jett's fiddles just like all the rest of them.
跟我们穿上粉红高跟鞋 像我们其他人般在杰特的 清幽小提琴伴奏下起舞
Well, if we go, then we'll do it right.
我们去便要形式正确
We're oil rich just like the rest of them...
我们是通过石油致富的 跟他们 其他人一样
...so we'll go like the rest of them, only better.
所以我们前去也要 跟他们一样 甚至更好
- Now you're talking like my father. The old Benedict spirit.
你现在说话倒像我父亲了 这就是老一辈 本尼迪特的精神了
Set up one of your grand weekends.
你会过上几个愉快的周末
Invite everybody. We'll take them down there with us.
我们要请完所有人 把他们都带去
We'll show that so-and-so who's top people around this part of the country.
让他们看看在 这片土地上谁更厉害
I'll even buy that four-engine Douglas.
我还要买一辆 四引擎的道格拉斯飞机
You can fly in some orchids from Hawaii.
你可以在夏威夷飞进花丛中
We'll load up our party, buzz in low on top of that building...
我们从酒店楼顶
...shake the tiles right off that hotel roof.
掀开砖头飞进去
Oh, there's Lola Lane.
是洛拉.莲
- I'll bet even Hollywood isn't so exciting. - Isn't it something?
我敢肯定即使是 好莱坞也没这么热闹
It's perfectly fabulous.
-真夸张啊? -太夸张了
Jett's always trying to do things bigger and spend more money than anybody else.
杰特总是要把自己的风头 弄得无与伦比… 情愿比别人出更多的钱
I can't wait to meet him. What does he do?
真的吗?他是干什么的?
To some he's just a no-good so-and-so.
对一些人来说
Cars for the Benedict party.
他只是个盲目钻探的傻瓜
There he is.
说曹操曹操就到
There's the emperor himself.
那个就是我们的"皇帝"了
Hey, isn't this terrific? Look at Luz. She's queen of the parade.
是不是很宏大?看卢斯 她居然是游行队伍中的皇后
You didn't tell me.
你没跟我说过
You know about this, Leslie?
你知不知道这事 莱斯利?
No, I didn't.
不 不知道
Oh, Lord.
噢 天哪
My daughter, queen of Jett Rink Day. What is this?
我女儿居然是杰特.林克 游行中的皇后 这算什么?
I don't know, Jordan.
我不知道 乔丹
She's done things before I haven't gone along with, but this... She's never been sneaky.
她居然没经过 我同意便私自下决定
It's not exactly sneaky, Jordan, appearing in a parade.
实在是太可恶了 在游行中抛头露脸 根本不是什么可恶
Don't try to be funny.
别开玩笑了
I'm not. I'm just as upset as you are.
我没开玩笑 我和你一样烦呢
I just know that Luz is intelligent enough not to be imposed on by anyone.
但我相信卢斯够聪明的 不会让他或者其他任何人骗的
Give me the desk.
帮我接柜台
This is Bick Benedict. Did my daughter Luz Benedict come in yet?
我是毕克本尼迪特 我女儿卢斯 本尼迪特回来了吗?
Now, get this. As soon as she comes in, have her call me.
给我记下 她一进酒店就叫她给我电话
Say, Luz...
听着 卢斯
You know what I think I'll do?
知道我会怎么做吗?
Hmm?
嗯?
I'm gonna keep it just like this.
我会这样做
I'll keep all those people, send them home.
把所有人留下来 然后送他们回家
I'm not even gonna open up this place.
甚至根本不打算开发这地方
Some girls might like a hotel all to themselves.
有些女孩希罕住高级的酒店
Me, I like company, Jett. I like lots of people.
而我 我喜欢有人陪伴 杰特 我喜欢许多人聚集在一起
Well, all right. All right.
好啊
You want lots of people?
你想要许多人陪伴?
I don't see any problem there.
我不觉得有什么问题
Honey...
亲爱的
...if there's anything you want...
有什么需要只管说出来
...you just say it and you've got it.
然后你就能得到了
All right, I'd like a Coke.
好啊 我要一杯可乐
Whew. Ha, ha.
呼 哈 哈
Oh, now, that's impossible. That's just impossible.
不 不可能 就这不可能
You know as well as I do, Cokes are taboo. All soft drinks.
你跟我一样清楚 可乐是这里的禁忌品 那些都是些软饮料
You make the rules.
随你便吧
I make the rules.
你喜欢事情按
You like things your own way, don't you, Jett?
你自己的意愿发展?
Let me ask you something.
我来问你些事
Do you like things your way?
你喜欢事情按你所想发展吗?
Not very many people have things their way, do they?
不是很多人可以随心所欲的
I don't get them my way very often.
我也很多事不能随心所欲
Nope.
不
And you won't either, until you get married...
你也不会 除非你结了婚…
...get your man to give you what you want when you want it.
让你老头子给你任何你想要的东西
So?
那么…
So if I was you, I'd start thinking about getting married.
那么如果我是你的话 我就会开始考虑结婚了
Well, that's an idea.
这主意很不错
You looked like a queen in that parade today.
今天的游行中 你看上去真像一个皇后
That was my job.
那是我的工作
It's just what you are...
事实上你就是一个皇后
...Luz Benedict Il.
卢斯本尼迪特二世
You know, you could be the head lady of this part of the whole country.
在整个国家的这片土地 你可以成为最令人瞩目的小姐
If you wanted to. lf you married right. If you married the right man.
如果你想的话 如果你嫁对人的话
Hmm, that's a sweet idea.
真甜蜜的好主意
Why don't I just announce it tonight...
我今晚为什么 不当众宣布出来呢…
...all them thousands of people out there just sitting, listening?
让那几千人在下面倾听?
The whole of Texas.
让整个德州的人都听到
Boy, wouldn't that blow the roof off?
会不会笑掉人家大牙?
Jett, tell me something.
杰特 告诉我
Hmm?
恩?
- Is this a proposal? - Does it sound like one?
你这算求婚吗? 听起来像求婚吗?
Oh, after a fashion, but not quite.
勉强算 但不确实
What do you want me to say? You want me to say something you can laugh at?
你想我说出一些 会让你大笑的话?
No.
不
What I wanted to say is I think you're a wonderful girl.
我只是认为 你是个迷人的女孩
And I do think you're beautiful, and I think...
而且你很美
You're fascinating to me, and I've always been looking...
我对你着迷 我一直在找寻一个…
...for a girl like you.
如你般的女孩
That sure would blow the roof off, wouldn't it?
是不是笑掉你大牙了?
Hey, you've got a long way to go tonight.
今晚还长着呢
Look, I'm very flattered. Any girl would be.
我受宠若惊了 所有女人都会这么觉得
You be a good boy, now.
听话 现在
I'll see you later.
我们迟些见
I hope the storm doesn't louse up your party, Mr. Rink.
希望这场风暴 没破坏了你的派对
Slip-up, boy. I just forgot to order the right kind of weather.
是我疏忽 我忘了 "预定"一份正确的天气了呢
I heard a twister hit Waco.
听说有龙卷风
What's the matter? Can't you talk United States?
你怎么回事? 你就不能说英语
You're talking to my wife.
你在跟我妻子说话啊
My name's Benedict, Jordan Benedict, if that means anything to you.
我是乔丹.本尼迪特 不知道你有没有印象
Okay, Mr. Benedict. I was just following orders.
我只是遵照吩咐做
Mr. Rink said he'd have my neck if I let any wrong people in.
林克先生说如果我让一些 不相干的人进了 去他就扭掉我脖子
- Benedict. Jordan Benedict. - Registering, please.
本尼迪特家人住的都很近
You Benedicts are all close together. They've got the Coronado Suite.
他们住在科罗纳多套房
You're in the Fernando Suite.
你住在菲兰多套间
I'm a mess. I must go to the beauty parlor.
我看起来糟透了 我得去美容院做做美容
You run for it before they close.
赶紧去 赶在晚会结束之前回来
The grand opening of the Jett Rink Airport and Emperador Hotel...
杰特.林克机场和 帝国酒店的盛大开张…
...is the latest milestone in the dramatic life of this virile son of Texas.
是我们来自德州的这位充满 粗犷魅力的小子戏剧人生的又一 个
Virile so-and-so.
雄起
Howdy, everybody.
各位好啊
Hi, Adarene.
你好 阿德雷妮
- About time you got here. - Where's Pinky, the old bat?
-你也该来了 -男孩们呢? "宾奇"在哪啊?那老头
Fernando Suite for Mr. Benedict, please.
请接电话 是本尼迪特先生 所住的菲兰多套间打来的
Beauty salon. - Can you take me?
这里是美容院 你们能帮我做个美容吗?
Yes, if you can come right along.
当然 只要你马上下来
Ha, ha. Thank goodness. I'll be right in.
谢谢 我马上过来
- Who's calling, please? - Mrs. Benedict.
-请问是谁打电话呢? -本尼迪特太太
- You come right along, Mrs. Benedict. - Ha, ha. Thank you.
快来吧 本尼迪特太太 谢谢
- Bawley. - Yo.
勃利 -来了
Keep everybody freshened up. We'll be with you quick.
先让大家振奋起来 我们很快出来
We're anxious to see old Jett come out of that chute.
真期待突然见到老鬼杰特 从那件衣服上突然钻出来
Why couldn't they ride with us the way other people's kids do?
为什么他们不像其他人的孩子 一样跟我们一起开车来?
No, Luz had to fly her own plane, and Jordy and Juana had to drive.
卢斯要坐自己的飞机 乔丹和胡安娜要开车前来
Thank you.
谢谢你
Anybody here?
有人吗?
We're all booked up.
我们预约满了
I just called. I'm Mrs. Benedict.
我刚刚打过电话来的 我是本尼迪特太太
I'm sorry, but we're busy.
对不起 但我们现在很忙
I wait a little.
那我稍等一下好了
They're driving. It takes time.
他们正在开车赶来了 这需要时间
Oh, I know it takes time, I know it.
我知道这需要时间
I made the trip myself 400 times.
这段路程我自己也开过400次
But don't worry about the children.
但别担心孩子们
Their behavior is odd, but their manners are beautiful.
他们举止虽异常 但他们的态度还是蛮好的
Now, listen here, boy. I've taken just about enough of this from you.
你给我听着! 我受够你了
I didn't want to come in the first place.
我当初根本不想来这里的
I wouldn't be here unless you'd let them bully you into it.
要不是你被他们威逼利诱 一番就吓坏了 我怎么会来
Now, for heaven's sakes, let's make the best of it.
既然来了 就看在上帝份上 好好利用这段时间
If you'll cool down, go on shaving, and finish dressing, I'll go down with you.
冷静点 继续刮你的胡子 穿好衣服 我等下就和你一起下去
Otherwise, you can go alone.
要不然你就给 我自己一个人下去吧
You know, honey...
宝贝…
...you're awful cute when you get riled.
你发怒时的样子 真是可爱极了
- Hello, Mr. Benedict. - Hello, Uncle Bawley.
你好 本尼迪特 -你好 勃利叔叔
Hey, Jordy.
嗨 乔丹
You better hurry on in there. Your ma and pa are sure having a battle. Whew.
快进去吧 你老爸老妈好像在开仗了
- Hello, honey. - Well, where have you been?
你好 宝贝 去了哪里?
We got tied up in traffic in town.
交通堵塞 迟到了一会
- Where's Juana? - She's in the beauty parlor.
胡安娜呢? 她去了美容院
Here, darling. Hello, sweetheart. - Where's Lupe?
你好啊 小宝贝
He's all right. He just didn't get his nap.
没事的 他只是没有睡够
How's my child, Grandpa Benedict?
我的孩子怎么了?
Is that Judy crying?
是不是茱迪在哭啊?
Oh, I hope I'm not too late. - Not too, come right in.
希望我不算太迟 没有 快进来
Yeah?
谁?
Oh, hello, Juana. Yeah, he's here.
你好啊 胡安娜
Jordy, it's for you.
他在 乔丹 找你的
Yes, dear?
什么事 宝贝?
Well, you stay right there, honey. I'm coming right down.
在那里等我 我马上下来
Don't you folks wait on us. We'll catch up.
你们不用等我 我马上回来
Son, you're way behind.
孩子 你来迟了好久
Howdy, everybody. Look who we found.
各位好 看看谁来了
Well, there you are.
你在这里
We were getting worried.
我们都有点担心了
Say, you'd better get dressed, Jett.
你最好快穿衣服了 杰特
Oh, yeah.
额 好的
You wanted me to go over the speech with you too.
你还要我跟你 一起过一遍演讲的
Come on, we better hurry.
快啊 我们得赶紧了
Well, I'm sorry, but it happens to be Mr. Jett Rink's orders.
对不起 但这是 杰特.林克先生的吩咐
And I'm just working here.
我只是在这打份工而已
It's everybody's orders. Same all over town.
我们对所有人都得遵守这吩咐 全城一视同仁
The young lady should've gone to a place where they do her people.
这位小姐应该去那些 帮他们的同胞做美容的地方
Well, if it isn't the queen herself.
这不是我们的皇后吗?
Hi. You having fun?
-还开心吧? -正在制造乐趣呢?
We're making out. How you doing?
-你好吗?         -很好
Good. Where are they, Mom and Dad?
我爸爸妈妈呢?
Don't trifle with your luck.
别把你的运气 视同儿戏哦（你可真有运哦）
There you are.
你来了
Oh, you want to talk to me, Dad?
爸爸 要和我说几句吗?
Yes, if you can spare me a few moments of your time, I'd like to talk to you.
小姐 如果你能给我几分钟的话 我想跟你谈些问题
Oh, Dad, must we now? - Yes.
现在必须谈吗? 爸爸?
We must hurry if we're gonna be on time for the grand entrance.
乔丹 我们得赶快到前厅去了
Oh, Luz, darling, you look just beautiful.
卢斯 亲爱的 你看起来美极了
Uncle Bawley, help me round everybody up.
能帮我带大家出来吗
I'm sorry I'm so late.
真抱歉迟到了那么久
All right, people. Hyah, hyah, hyah!
好了 各位…
Hyah, hyah, hyah!
哈 哈 哈
Get along, there.
大家静一静
There's a clause here...
这儿有个条款
Did some of you boys change this?
你们有改动过吗?
Lord, man, no. We haven't changed a single comma.
连标点符号都没有改动过
Changes tend to throw you.
似乎你不喜欢我们更动
"Columbus discovered only the shell of this country.
哥伦布发现了 这个国家的外壳
- Agassiz came and discovered fossil... " - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
阿加西…
Members only.
仅限会员
Where's Rink?
林克呢?
He went that way.
他从那走了
Looks like I just come in for a root beer. Ha-ha-ha.
好像来这喝东西一样
That, my friend, is a Texas rain.
朋友 德州的
Hey, Bick. What you doing sitting up there? Come on, sit at our table, boy.
你们在那坐着干吗?
the Texan said, "Paul Revere?
"你们听说过保罗.李维尔没有? "德州人说:"保罗.李维尔?"
Oh, yeah, ain't he the fella that had to ride for help?"
"噢 对了 不就是那个 策马过来帮忙的家伙吗?"
In just a few moments...
在几分钟之后
...Mr. Rink himself will be here at the microphone.
林克先生本人… 就会在麦克风前
Come on, let's go.
快 我们走
Jordy smashed up the beauty parlor.
乔丹正在到处找杰特.林克
- He's looking for. - What?
什么?
Where we have our hair done.
缘起于我们做头发那里
Jordy's looking for Jett to fight him, says it was his orders.
乔丹要狠揍杰特 因为那是他主意
- Why? - Juana. The girl said they didn't take wetbacks.
由于胡安娜原因 美容院女孩说 他们不帮"湿背人"美容
... of our entire country. Thank you, Congressman Bale Clinch.
The eyes of Texas are upon you
You cannot get away
Do not think you can escape them
At night or early in the morn
The eyes of Texas are upon you
Till Gabriel blows his horn
Stay here, honey. I'll be right back.
在这等我 宝贝 我马上回来
All the livelong day
The eyes of Texas are upon you
You cannot get away
Is this young Benedict? - You invited me down here to insult my wife.
你邀请我来就为了凌辱我的妻子?
And you're gonna answer for it.
你必须对此负责
Aren't you the one who married a squaw?
你不就是那个娶了 印第安女人做老婆的那个吗?
What's the matter? Ain't you having a good time?
怎么了 小子?在这不爽?
Get them up, Rink. Everybody knows you got this coming to you.
把拳头举起来 林克 人人都知道你应该受到这样惩罚
- Jordy, no. - Get them up, Rink. Let go of me.
乔丹 不要!
You want it now, in front of everybody...
你是想在人前
...or you want to come outside?
还是去外面?
I don't care much...
我可不管是
...whether it's here or outside...
在这里还是在外面…
...so long as I get one punch at that stuck-up face of yours.
只要我愿意给你的脸一拳
Sit down, sit down.
坐下
Heh, heh. Governor, how are you this evening?
州长 今晚还好吧?
Fine.
好的
And now to introduce our guest of honor...
现在 我们来介绍 我们的荣誉嘉宾
...we hear from a man known from the rocky coast of Maine...
坐在我们这里的…
...to the Golden Gate in California.
是自缅因州到加利 福尼亚州无人不识的…
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士们先生们 我们的…
...our own Senator Oliver Whiteside.
参议员奥利弗.怀特赛德
Mr. Toastmaster...
尊敬的宴会主持人...
...Governor North...
...州长
...ladies and gentlemen...
...女士们先生们
The eyes of the entire nation are on us tonight...
全国的的目光今晚都聚集在我们身上
...as we gather here to honor them...
今晚 我们聚在一起纪念那些...
Get them up.
举起拳头
You had this coming to you for a long time.
你早该受我几拳了
Texas has been kind to Jett Rink...
德克萨斯对杰特·林克太宽容了...
...and is ever ready...
...时刻准备包庇他
You're gonna get what you gave my boy.
你怎么揍我孩子 我就怎么揍回你
Get them up. Get them up!
举起拳头 举起拳头!
proud, friendly...
…骄傲 友好…
...warm-hearted, successful.
热心 成功
Yes, successful, I am sure...
没错 我相信必定成功…
...beyond his wildest dreams.
...超越最狂野的梦想
But Jett Rink has never lost the common touch.
...但是杰特·林克的民意支持度一直很高
You ain't even worth hitting.
你根本不值得我去揍
Jett, you want to know something true?
想知道一些真实的事吗?
You're all through.
你早就什么也不是了
... all old friends who have known him and loved him...
...所有了解他 爱过他的老朋友
...since boyhood.
从小就认识他
Dear friends...
朋友们
...I'm going to ask you to come with me tonight...
今晚 我们大家来…
...as I turn back the pages in my book of happy memories...
一起回顾 一些美好的回忆
...and I recall the first time I saw young Jett Rink.
我记得首次见到 年轻的杰特.林克的情形
- Where's the boy? He went upstairs.
-那孩子呢? -胡安娜扶他上楼了
Come on, let's get out of here.
我们走吧
I'll go get Luz. - Hurry up.
我去叫卢斯 快点
moves the sand of glorious...
带走光辉...
Luz, we're leaving.
来 卢斯 我们走
- in his face shone that light... - Would you excuse me, please?
-能让一下吗?
that destiny always uses...
命运总是...
The years pass quickly, as the years have a way of doing.
光阴似箭… 这是光阴的习惯
And now I see Jett Rink as a young man...
如今我见到的杰特.林克…
... afraid of neither opposition nor hard work...
是一个既不害怕别人反对 也不惧怕辛劳工作的 杰特.林克…
...his eyes set on a far distant goal towards which he's ever working...
他目光远大… 在工作中 计划中 奋斗中…
...learning, striving.
一步步实现自己的目标
And now we come to Jett Rink, the man.
现在我们的 杰特.林克进来了
Texas has been kind to Jett Rink.
德州是给了 杰特.林克许多机遇的地方
And Jett, never forgetting this kindness...
杰特也从来没有忘记 过德州给他的机遇…
...is ever ready to devote his resources...
他随时愿意 捐献出自己的资源…
...to the greater glory of the state which reared him...
给这片培养了他的土地…
...and which, in turn, does honor to him tonight...
这片土地也回报 以他今晚的荣耀
...in this great gathering here present.
回报以各位如此聚集一堂
And now, my friends, here...
现在 在这里的朋友们…
...and to the many thousands of you listening across the nation...
全国收听着 广播的千万人民们…
...I have the privilege...
我非常荣幸…
...yes, I have the great honor...
荣幸之极给大家介绍
...to introduce a legend in his own time...
一个这个时代的传奇…
...a great Texan...
一名伟大的德州人…
...an outstanding American...
杰出的美国人!
...yes, my friends, a man.
没错 朋友们 就是他!
I give to you Jett Rink.
我们有我们的杰特.林克!
All the livelong day
The eyes of Texas are upon you
You cannot get away
Do not think you can escape them
At night or early in the morn
The eyes of Texas are upon you
Well, you can count on me.
你可以信得过我的
All right, then. Goodbye.
好吧 再见
How bad?
情况有多坏?
It hit pretty hard in Vientecito.
"文塞塔"受到了 很严重的袭击
Dr. Guerra set up an auxiliary hospital. He needs help. I better get down there.
吉埃拉医生开设了 临时辅助性的医院 他需要帮忙 我得马上过去
You'll make better time if you wait till first light and fly.
等到明早做第一班机吧 那会让你时间充裕些
I don't relish the idea of spending the night under Jett's roof.
我讨厌睡在 杰特的屋檐底下
Me too.
我也是
If it weren't for transporting this circus, we'd all hightail it out of here.
如果不是有约定 我们早就逃开了
I hope she don't let this upset her too much...
希望这不会令她太过不安
...this business tonight.
今晚的事…
It's just one of those things.
只是这些凌辱的其中之一
Best thing to do is forget about it.
最好的方式就是忘掉它
Yeah. Well, go ahead. You forget it.
对 忘掉它
Me, I'm gonna remember it.
但我一定要记住这事
Now, look, Jordy.
听着 乔丹
Take it easy.
别紧张
We've had just about enough excitement around here for one night.
我们才住一晚受的 刺激就差不多够了
- Yeah, I guess so. - Sure.
我猜是吧
You've always had a mind of your own, and you've always used it.
你一向都很有自己的主见 并且会充分实现自己的主见
Done things pretty near your own way.
你一直都是按自己的方式行事
You knew what you was doing when you married in that direction.
你那样结婚的时候你应该 已经知晓自己在干什么
I told you myself the morning after you broke the news. Remember?
你那天早上给我说 那消息时我就告诉过你 记得吗?
I told you then that I knew Juana was a mighty-fine little gal...
我告诉过你我知道胡安娜 是一个很好的女孩…
...but when you and she got married, you was asking for trouble. Remember?
但是娶她的话就意味着 自找麻烦 你记得吗?
I told you that.
我跟你说过的
Lots of folks in this part of the country are pretty jumpy about that sort of thing.
这里的许多人对 这种事都太神经质了
- Jett's only one of them. - I know those people.
杰特只是其中之一 我知道有这种人
Just leave them to heaven. We're doing fine.
我们以前也碰过这种事 但我们都处理得很好
Look, Papa, if I'm concerned, it has to do with the people that ought to know better.
我只担心怎么去对付 那些本来应该更了解我的人
Like my own father.
譬如我自己的父亲
- Hmm? - Just the simple truth, that's you.
很简单 就是你
That's the way you think.
你就是这么想的
Oh, good Lord, I don't care about Jett Rink.
我才不管什么杰特.林克
But you, Papa, that's different.
但是你 爸爸 那不同
Now, you look here, Jordy.
你给我听着 乔丹!
You can't talk to me like that.
你不能这么跟我说话!
Why, Lord, no man can.
谁都不能这么跟我说话!
I'm a fair man, and I've been fair all my life, with everybody.
我一向是个公正的人 一辈子正直无私 对所有人都是
And you, my own son, can't sit there and tell me that I'm not a fair man.
你 我的孩子 你不能跟我 这么说我不是个公正的人
Look, Jordy...
听着 乔丹…
...there's ways of living and there's ways of doing things that folks abide by...
生活有种种方式 做事有种种方式…
...when they want to live right and happily in comfort with their own people.
有人就喜欢和 自己的同胞一起… 觉得这样生活才算舒服 才开心
And I always say Juana's a mighty-fine little gal, but...
我一直都说胡安娜 是个好女孩 只是…
Don't sit there and prove what I say! I don't like to hear you do it.
别干坐在那里证明我说的话 我不想听到你这么说
Dang it, boy, you're not being fair.
你一点都不公正
When that ruckus started down there tonight, who went after Rink?
在那骚嚷时 是谁去跟林克挑战了?
Your old man.
是你爸爸!
Who took him to count? Your old man.
-谁为你出头?是你爸爸!
- And why? - Why? Because I...
-那为什么要帮我出头呢?
- Because of my wife? - Yes.
因为我妻子?
No. No, because your son...
-是的 -不是! 那是因为你儿子
...Jordan Benedict, descendant of the long, proud line of Reata...
乔丹.本尼迪特… "利塔"漫长而又 令你自豪的血统后代
...got knocked right flat on his back in front of all Texas. That's why.
因为他被当着整个德州狠狠 地被人羞辱了 这才是原因!
Now, look, Papa.
听着 爸爸
Just forget it. Don't worry yourself about it.
算了吧 别担心了
Look, Mama, I guess you made a big mistake...
妈妈 当你跟我们这些 好吵闹的德州人闹在了一起
...when you got yourself mixed up with us rowdy Texans.
你真是犯了个大错
Well, I'm shocked at you, and I'm shocked at all of us.
你真让我吃惊 你们所有人都太让我吃惊了
I'm just so ashamed.
我真羞愧
I'll never be able to forget the sight of my brother barging into the grand ballroom...
我永远不会忘记我哥哥 闯入豪华的前厅…
...disgracing us. Then my father had to make it a bigger brawl.
在我们朋友的面前 让我们丢脸!而我的父亲 随后把这脸丢得更大
I don't know when I'll be able to face people.
我以后还怎么见人啊?
Keep seeing Jett, you won't have to face me.
你继续去见杰特的话 就不用再见我了
Children.
孩子们!
Well, how about that, anyway, Mama?
这样怎样 妈妈?
I haven't been asked.
一直没人问我意见
It seems that my family just can't tolerate his success.
我们一家好像不能 容忍他的成功似的
- My darling Luz. - Well, tonight meant a lot to Jett.
亲爱的 卢斯 今晚对杰特意味非凡
Really, I know.
我知道的
If I only knew how to apologize to him, I'd go to him now.
真不知该怎么去跟他道歉 如果我知道的话我早去了
I can't face all those people.
但我不能再面对那些人
The party's over. They've all gone home.
派对早结束了 宾客们都回家了
All?
都?
He passed out like a light in front of the whole crowd.
他在大众面前晕了过去
- Oh, no. - That's what we heard, Luz.
不! 卢斯 这是我们听到的消息
Well, he must have been ill.
他一定是病了
Weak with shame or something.
或者是羞愧难当
He was plain drunk, if you'll forgive me.
也不祈求你能原谅 我直说吧 他纯粹是喝醉了
I don't believe you.
我才不信你
Party broke up early, but not a minute too soon.
派对提前散场了 但也不算快
Give me Mr. Rink's penthouse, please. Luz Benedict.
给我接林克先生的阁楼
You are not going up there, Luz, if I have to sit on you.
你不许上去 即使是要我把你 关在这里我也不许你上去
Well, it's important. Do you know where he is?
事情很紧要 你知道他在哪吗?
Luz, it's not like you to make a fool of yourself.
卢斯 在人前表现 这么愚蠢不像是你所为
I know where he is, honey.
我知道他在哪
Come along with your Uncle Bawley.
跟勃利叔叔一起来吧
All right, Luz.
好吧 卢斯
If you must go.
你真决定要走便走吧
I must.
我必须走
I've always held a strange power over your mother.
在你母亲面前我不知怎么的 总是有股神奇的力量
I'm sorry, Mother.
对不起 妈妈
What do you say, dollface?
你说什么 老板?
About ready to come along with your old pal now?
要跟我一起走了吗?
It's time we hit the hay.
是时候上去睡觉了
I give up.
算了 我放弃
- Can we go to work now? - Leave him alone.
我们能进去干活了吗? 别管他吧
He owns the place. Let him enjoy it.
这地方是他的 就让他好好在这玩一下吧
Shut up!
闭嘴! 闭嘴!
Ladies and gents...
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen, distinguished guests.
各位尊贵的宾客…
I just want to count the blessings...
我在此祈祷…
...that this great domain has bestowed upon her humble son.
这片土地仍记得 他卑微的子民…
My friends...
朋友们…
...this is a man.
这就是一个成功的人!
Old Mother Texas.
故土德州!
What did she give to me?
她给了我什么?
Not a goldarn thing.
什么都没有!
You gotta work and sweat and steal it from her.
你必须在这块土地上辛勤工作 挥洒汗水 从她身上偷掠拐骗
But I got mine...
但我的一切都是
...right out of the ground.
从这土地上而来的
Poor Jett...
可怜的杰特…
...fighting for what is good.
为美好的事物奋斗
Lucky.
充当奴仆!
Lucky for Bick Benedict...
充当毕克本尼迪特的奴仆
...her husband.
她丈夫的奴仆
Poor Jett.
可怜的杰特
Poor, pretty Leslie.
可怜美丽的莱斯利
Pretty Leslie.
美丽的莱斯利…
Pretty Leslie, wonderful, beautiful girl-bride.
美丽的莱斯利 完美 美丽的新娘
Poor boy.
可怜的孩子
Rich...
富足的…
...rich Mrs. Benedict.
富足的本尼迪特先生
She's beautiful.
她好美丽
Lovely.
可爱
The woman a man wants.
那是个吸引男人的女人
The woman a man's gotta have too.
也是个男人都要追求的女人
Thank you, Uncle Bawley.
谢谢你 勃利叔叔
Governor.
州长…
You know what you can do.
你知道你能干什么吗?
Down Mexico way
That's where I fell in love
When stars above came out
- Just as soon as it lands, I'm gonna sell it. - Good.
它一降落我就卖了它 很好
This is for me, boy. The simple life.
这才适合我 简单的生活
No more of this highflying nonsense.
我不再要这些 飞得高高的废物了
Say, Juana, how does a hamburger and a piece of pie sound to you?
胡安娜 觉得来一份汉堡包 和一片薄饼怎么样?
- Sounds very good. - A what?
听起来惹人极了
No more of this highfalutin stuff.
我们不去什么高级地方了
Let's stop in up here and have us some chicken.
就在这个普通的 汽车餐馆吃些鸡肉吧
Then we can eat it with our fingers.
可能好吃得连自己的 手指都会吞下去哦
- Over here, honey? Yeah.
过来 亲爱的 好的
- Howdy, folks. Good afternoon.
伙计们 中午好
Howdy.
你好
Nice place you have here. Been intending to stop...
你们这地方不错 我每次开车经过
- ...every time I drove by. - Thank you.
都想进来坐坐 谢谢
What do you recommend, landlord? How's fried chicken?
有什么好介绍?炸鸡怎样?
Little Jordy wants ice cream, Grandpa.
小乔丹想吃冰激凌 爷爷
Grandpa.
爷爷?
Ice cream it shall be.
冰激凌吗
Give the little fellow some ice cream.
那就给这小家伙 来份冰激凌吧
Ice cream? I thought that kid would want a tamale.
冰激凌? 我还以为他应该吃些 玉米面团包馅卷（墨西哥传统食
All right, sweetheart, give them what they want.
他们点什么给什么
What do you say, Juana? It's all right, isn't it?
怎么样?这样可以吗?
- It's good. Yes, sirree.
很好
After all that fancy food and high living, this is the life.
吃惯了山珍海味 住惯了高楼豪宅 这才是生活啊
Hey, you.
嘿 你们几个
Now, let's see, the big plane should be arriving in Benedict around 1:30.
飞机应该在一点半左右 就到达本尼迪特的了
You're in the wrong place, amigo.
你们来错地方了
Come on, let's get out of here.
走 我们出去
Your money's no good here.
你的钱在这里没用
Come on, let's go.
走吧!
- You too. - Hold on a minute.
你们也是 等等
Yes? What do you want?
怎样?有何指教?
Now, look here, Sarge.
大厨 听着
I'd sure appreciate it if you were a little more polite to these people.
如果你对这些人能 客气点我会非常感激的
Oh, you would, would you?
你会非常感激?
I'm Bick Benedict. Your neighbor, you might say.
我是毕克本尼迪特 你可以说我是你的邻居
Does that give you special privileges?
叫这名字就有什么特权吗?
The name Benedict's meant something to people around here for a considerable time.
本尼迪特这名字对周围的人 应该还是意味了一些东西的
That there papoose down there...
那边那个土孩子…
...his name Benedict too?
名字也叫本尼迪特吗?
Yeah, come to think of it.
是的 想想吧
It is.
没错
All right, forget I asked you.
当我没问过吧
Just go back and sit down, and we ain't gonna have no trouble.
你回去坐好 我们谁都别惹麻烦
But this bunch here's gonna eat somewheres else.
但这几个老土怪得 到别的地方去找东西吃
- All right, come on, let's go. You too. Sue me. - Take your hands off him.
好了 给我走吧 快 你们俩也是
Now, you're out of line, mister.
你这就不对了 先生
Poor Daddy.
可怜的爸爸
Just leave him alone!
把他一个人丢下了
Is that the best that old horse thief can do?
那大块头也就这能耐?
- He's feeling your mood. Simpatico, darling. - Hmm.
他觉察到你的心绪了 亲爱的
There's a lot of clair de lune in both of you old fire-eaters.
你们俩都有 一肚子的火爆脾气
You're both rather gentle creatures, you know.
但你们也都是 非常温柔的生物
How awful.
真恶心!
Those kids. Look at them.
你看… 那俩孩子
Those kids, in their infinite wisdom...
孩子们有着无限的智慧
...are smarter than we are.
着实比你我还要聪明
They know I'm a disgrace and don't hesitate to say so, either.
他们知道我很丢人 而他们不会犹豫去表现出来
Sure, even the calf's got my number.
甚至是那头小牛 都知道我丢人了
Well, I don't have to take it from a sheep.
小羊都知道也太丢人了吧
Now, Jordan.
好了 老乔丹!
Hello? Hello, Vashti.
你好啊 维斯泰
Oh, we're all fine.
我们很好
How'd you make it back?
你们回归了吗?
Good.
好
- They all made it back in one piece. - Jolly.
-回归一体了 -朱莉
Well, all the guests have finally gone.
对啊 我们的宾客都消失了
- Thank goodness. - Thank goodness.
谢天谢地
But more have left than we bargained for.
但却留下了更多东西处理
Luz has gone on to Hollywood with...
卢斯跟洛拉还是 什么的去了好莱坞
...Lona or Lola or whatever her name was.
她决定去好莱坞 看看适不适合她
She decided she'd like to see how she liked Hollywood.
我们家还没有过 电影明星呢
- No, we've never had one, not on this side. - Good lord, an actress.
是的 我们从来没有过 这方面都没有 -天哪 演员
Well, Vashti...
听着 维斯泰
...all you can do is raise them.
你能做到的只是把他们带大
You can't live their lives for them.
不能代他们过活
No. Judy and Bob are out looking at a ranch.
茱迪和鲍勃在 照看一家农场
A small one.
很小的一家农场
Yeah. Jordy and Juana are gonna move into Vientecito.
乔丹和胡安娜 打算搬进去文塞塔
And we, we're home minding the babies.
我们吗 我们就在家照看小宝贝咯
Hey, Bick? - Huh?
嘿 毕克 -嗯?
The sun's going down over the yardarm.
太阳下山了
- When are you gonna open up the bar? - Anytime, go ahead.
什么时候开张酒吧啊? 随时 来吧
Just remember, one day, that bourbon's gonna kill you.
记住 总有一天这些 威士忌会把你干掉
Okay. It'll be me or it.
好了 不知是我干掉它 还是它干掉我
One of us has gotta go.
我们总有一个要走
Oh, me?
恩 我?
I'm gonna stay right here.
我要留在这里
It's coming on spring.
快到春天了
Roundup time is no time to be away from Reata.
放牧的季节我们怎能离开
Yes, dear. Mm-hm.
是的 亲爱的
Okay.
好的
Bye-bye.
再见
Yeah, honey, everybody's on the move. Strays leaving the herd.
宝贝 每个人都在走动 甚至连河流都在 离开我们的牧群了
I suppose I wouldn't mind it too much...
如果你想收拾行李暂时回家
...if you wanted to go pack up and go back home for a spell.
我不会介意的
Home?
回家?
Where do you think I've been this last breathless quarter of a century?
你以为我累得气喘吁吁的 四分之一世纪里面 都呆在哪里了啊?
Home.
家?
Look, boy, I belong here.
听着 小子 我属于这里
You really want to know what's gotten my goat?
你真想知道为什么 那头羊会这样叫?
What, honey?
什么 亲爱的?
My own grandson don't even look like one of us.
我们唯一的孙子 看起来也不大像我们
So help me, he looks like a little wetback.
他看起来真像个"湿背人"
- Jordan. - Well...
乔丹 -好吧
Little muchacho fires up, don't he?
小家伙生气了?
Well, I'm sorry, Jordan Benedict IV.
对不起啊 乔丹.本尼迪特四世
There's times a man just has to be honest.
有时人总该老实一点
You know something, Leslie?
你知道吗 莱斯利?
There's no use for kidding, either.
我不是开玩笑
I'm a failure.
我其实是个失败者
Nothing just turned out like I'd planned.
没有什么是按照我 所想去实现的
I just... I just feel like my saddle's...
甚至连马鞍我都
...turning right out from under me.
觉得会抽身离去了
Do want to know something, Jordan?
你想知道些事吗?
I think you're great.
我认为你棒极了
Oh, don't ask me why. There are some things that are difficult to explain.
别问我为什么 有些事情很难解释
You know all that fine riding you used to do, and all that fancy roping...
你以前骑马骑得很棒 用绳索出神入化…
...and all that glamour stuff you did to dazzle me?
还有一切一切让 我简直眼花缭乱的魔术
Oh, it was impressive.
的确是让人印象深刻
But none of it ever made you quite as big a man to me...
但那些都不足以使你在 我心中成为一个伟大的人…
...as you were on the floor of Sarge's hamburger joint.
只有那天 你倒在了 那家餐馆的地上 我倒觉得了
When you tumbled rearward and landed crashing...
当你往后倒下时…
...into that pile of dirty dishes...
把整盘肮脏的菜都扣翻时
...you were at last my hero.
你最终成为了 我心中的英雄
That's what you always wanted to be, you know.
而那是你一直想做的
Could be.
可能是吧
When we went into that place, before the fight started...
我们进去时 在那场打斗开始前…
Oh. Oh, what a fight. It was glorious.
真是一场美妙的打斗! 太棒了
Before we went into that place...
在我们进去前
...I was feeling like you are now.
我正有你现在的感觉
I was thinking to myself:
我在暗地里想:
"Well, Jordan and I...
"嗯…"
...and all the others behind us have been failures."
乔丹 我 还有我们家族之前人  都是失败者
And then it happened.
然后事情就发生了
You wound up on the floor, on your back...
你倒在了地上
...in the middle of the salad.
倒在了一盘色拉中间
And I said to myself:
我对自己说:
"Well, after a hundred years...
"嗯…"
...the Benedict family...
"经过100了年…"
...is a real big success."
"本尼迪特家族…" "终于赢得真正的成功了"
You want to know something, Leslie?
想知道些事吗 莱斯利?
If I live to be 90...
如果我能活到90岁…
...I'm never gonna be able to figure you out.
即使到那时候 我也不会忘记你